{"content": "Square, Colombo 7 on 25th  September 2018 at 9.30 a.m. and 1.  To receive and consider the Annual Report of the Board of Report of the Auditors thereon. 2.  To  re-elect  as  a  Director  Mr.  C  M  O  Haglind  who  retires Association of the Company. 3.  To pass the ordinary resolution set out below to re- appoint Mr. G V M Nanayakkara who is over 70 years of age, as a Section 210 of the Companies Act, No.07 of 2007 shall not apply to Mr. G V M Nanayakkara who is over 70 years of Act No. 07 of 2007” 4.  To authorise the Directors to determine donations for the 5.  To re-appoint Messrs. BDO Partners, Chartered Accountants to determine their remuneration.","annotation":[{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":440,"end":460,"text":"Mr. G V M Nanayakkara"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":392,"end":419,"text":"Companies Act, No.07 of 2007"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":317,"end":337,"text":"Mr. G V M Nanayakkara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":188,"end":208,"text":"Mr.  C  M  O  Haglind"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550249413000,"last_updated_at":1550249413000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "financial year ending 31st March 2018. It is with pleasure that I uncertainties and challenges.","annotation":[{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":22,"end":36,"text":"31st March 2018"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550253363000,"last_updated_at":1550253363000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "The impact of climate change was dry  spell  leading  to  some  drought  conditions.  Such  extreme detrimental impacts on the tea industry.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":127,"end":129,"text":"tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251296000,"last_updated_at":1550251296000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "which  is  a  significant  increase  from  the  preceding  year.  The United Arab Emirates leading the fray.","annotation":[{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":70,"end":89,"text":"United Arab Emirates"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251870000,"last_updated_at":1550251870000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "of total tea exports valued at US $ 1.6 Billion, closely followed by Sri Lanka accounting for 19.3% of total tea exports with a value of US $ 1.5 Billion. Kenya (18.2% / US $ 1.4 Billion) and India (7.5% / US $ 591.2 Million) have experienced decreases in tea exports in value terms from the previous year.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":256,"end":258,"text":"tea"}]},{"label":["LOC"],"points":[{"start":192,"end":197,"text":"India "}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":155,"end":159,"text":"Kenya"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":109,"end":111,"text":"tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":69,"end":77,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":9,"end":11,"text":"tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251368000,"last_updated_at":1550251368000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "which can be leveraged by the tea exporters. The consumption choices,  centered  on  health,  environment  and  community. with the ethos of Bogawantalawa.","annotation":[{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":141,"end":153,"text":"Bogawantalawa"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":30,"end":32,"text":"tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251209000,"last_updated_at":1550251218000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Furthermore, the growth of capabilities to compete and win in such market segments. achieved a turnover of Rs. 3,436 Million, being the highest in its history with the turnover at group level reaching Rs. 4.8 Billion (Rs. 4.2 Billion in the year 2016/17). Profit before taxation of the company peaked at Rs. 366.8 million, which is a 289% increase from the preceding financial year. The comprehensive income for the year, net of taxes works out to Rs. 220.5 Million, after taking  in  to  account  the  deferred  tax  expense  of  Rs.  185.9 Million.","annotation":[{"label":["MONEY"],"points":[{"start":531,"end":548,"text":"Rs.  185.9 Million"}]},{"label":["MONEY"],"points":[{"start":304,"end":320,"text":"Rs. 366.8 million"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251282000,"last_updated_at":1550251282000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "company's selling price of tea has increased by 31.5% from the previous year 2016/17 to record the highest NSA of Rs. 619/= per kilo.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":27,"end":29,"text":"tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550248848000,"last_updated_at":1550248848000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "integral in the corporate eco-system of the company. Bogawantalawa  tea  looks  very  positive.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":53,"end":70,"text":"Bogawantalawa  tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550248970000,"last_updated_at":1550248970000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "The  Board  is  confident  that  the management team inspired by company Vision and Mission. finest  Ceylon  Tea  since  1869.  Bogawantalawa  Tea  Estates products.","annotation":[{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":128,"end":154,"text":"Bogawantalawa  Tea  Estates"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550249834000,"last_updated_at":1550249834000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Sustainability is a way of life at Bogawantalawa Tea Estates PLC.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":35,"end":63,"text":"Bogawantalawa Tea Estates PLC"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550253375000,"last_updated_at":1550253375000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "of  Organization  CFP  was  ISO  14064:  Part  01.  Scope  was  the cradle of plantation to shipping point of marketing division.","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":28,"end":37,"text":"ISO  14064"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251331000,"last_updated_at":1550251331000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Total GHG emissions, per one kilogram of made tea was 0.21 kg of CO2 equivalent and it with Sri Lanka Carbon Credit Scheme.","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":92,"end":121,"text":"Sri Lanka Carbon Credit Scheme"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":46,"end":48,"text":"tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550252458000,"last_updated_at":1550252458000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Installed capacities and potential power generations are as follows. 3.2 MW has commissioned within the plantation as  projects  and  internal  systems.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":35,"end":51,"text":"power generations"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550249713000,"last_updated_at":1550249713000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Although the factors for solar generations in Up Country area. 780 kW has already installed and 1.2MW will be installed. Sustainability Report Contd. The total potential GHG saving from our Renewable Energy development projects is approximately 30,088 tons / Yr.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":25,"end":41,"text":"solar generations"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550252960000,"last_updated_at":1550252960000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "distinctiveness. There are three main objectives of the plantation benefits. Largest timber nursery of Sri Lanka is owned by the plants.","annotation":[{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":103,"end":111,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":85,"end":90,"text":"timber"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550252746000,"last_updated_at":1550252746000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Sustainability Report Contd. burial  of  pruning,  draining,  compost  application  etc.  since productivity improvement in tea plantations.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":124,"end":126,"text":"tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550252113000,"last_updated_at":1550252113000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Sustainability Report Contd. are  an  integral  part  of  who  we  are.  Our  family  extends  not around  Tea  plantation  and  beyond  as  well.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":107,"end":109,"text":"Tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550249131000,"last_updated_at":1550249131000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "In order to reduce the refilling expenses, households use both firewood and LPG.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":63,"end":70,"text":"firewood"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550249903000,"last_updated_at":1550249903000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "2 MR.D A D E S WICKRAMANAYAKE 4 MR M.M. FUAD 5 DR.R D BANDARANAIKE 7 MR A.K. SENEVIRATNE 8 MRS K.G.M. PIERIS 10 MRS N.A. EDIRIWEERA 16 DR D. RAJAKANTHAN 17 MR K. RAJAKANTHAN 18 MRS F.F. HANIFA 19 MR K.S.M. RODRIGO 20 MR R.E. RAMBUKWELLE Investor Information Contd. Rs. 19.50 (01.11.2017) Rs.   8.00 (06.04.2017) Rs.   16.00 Rs. 11.70 (12.04.2016) Rs.   7.60 (23.03.2017) Rs.   7.90 Value of shares traded during the year (Rs.) 11  The Public Holding Percentage as at 31st March 2018 being 10.1343% 13  The Float adjusted market capitalization as at 31st March 2018 - Rs. 135,799,792.00 effect from 02nd July 2018. The Float adjusted market capitalization of the Company falls under Option 2 of Rule 7.13.1(b) of the Listing Rules of the said Option.","annotation":[{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":549,"end":563,"text":"31st March 2018"}]},{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":467,"end":481,"text":"31st March 2018"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":217,"end":235,"text":"MR R.E. RAMBUKWELLE"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":196,"end":212,"text":"MR K.S.M. RODRIGO"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":177,"end":191,"text":"MRS F.F. HANIFA"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":156,"end":172,"text":"MR K. RAJAKANTHAN"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":135,"end":151,"text":"DR D. RAJAKANTHAN"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":112,"end":130,"text":"MRS N.A. EDIRIWEERA"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":91,"end":107,"text":"MRS K.G.M. PIERIS"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":69,"end":87,"text":"MR A.K. SENEVIRATNE"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":32,"end":65,"text":"MR M.M. FUAD 5 DR.R D BANDARANAIKE"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":2,"end":28,"text":"MR.D A D E S WICKRAMANAYAKE"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550249629000,"last_updated_at":1550249629000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Mr.  Don  Ariyaseela  De  Silva  Wickramanayake  is  the  present Chairman/Managing  Director  of  Master  Divers  (Pvt)  Ltd., Nautical Engineering.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":85,"end":125,"text":"Director  of  Master  Divers  (Pvt)  Ltd."}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":46,"text":"Mr.  Don  Ariyaseela  De  Silva  Wickramanayake"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550253319000,"last_updated_at":1550253319000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "At  present  he  serves  as  the  Executive  Deputy of Metropolitan Resource Holdings (Pvt) Ltd. Mr.  Gerard  Victor  Mauric  Nanayakkara  is  a  Fellow  of  the Kingdom.    He  has  over  40  years’  experience    in    finance Development  Authority  &  Colombo  Commercial  Co.  Ltd). restructuring/financing transactions.","annotation":[{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":97,"end":136,"text":"Mr.  Gerard  Victor  Mauric  Nanayakkara"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":55,"end":95,"text":"Metropolitan Resource Holdings (Pvt) Ltd."}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550252597000,"last_updated_at":1550252597000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Mr. Dinesh Jamnadas Ambani is the present Chairman of the Ceylon Tea Gardens Ltd. -  Megatech (Pvt) Ltd. -  Ceylon Bungalows (Pvt) Ltd. -  Areva Investments (Pvt) Ltd. Mr.  Lalithkumar  Jamnadas  Ambani  is  a  fellow  Member  of Accountants.","annotation":[{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":168,"end":201,"text":"Mr.  Lalithkumar  Jamnadas  Ambani"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":139,"end":166,"text":"Areva Investments (Pvt) Ltd."}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":108,"end":134,"text":"Ceylon Bungalows (Pvt) Ltd."}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":85,"end":103,"text":"Megatech (Pvt) Ltd."}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":58,"end":80,"text":"Ceylon Tea Gardens Ltd."}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":25,"text":"Mr. Dinesh Jamnadas Ambani"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550253418000,"last_updated_at":1550253418000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Mr. Carl Michael Oscarsson Haglind has a MSc from Stockholm School of Economics. He is the President of Exilesoft, Director of Earnd’it and Nex2Do.","annotation":[{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":33,"text":"Mr. Carl Michael Oscarsson Haglind"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251934000,"last_updated_at":1550251934000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Mr. Sudath Ajitha Samaradivakara Jayasundara has a Bachelor of  Law (LL.B) from the University of Colombo and is an Attorney- Courts of Sri Lanka.","annotation":[{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":43,"text":"Mr. Sudath Ajitha Samaradivakara Jayasundara"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251186000,"last_updated_at":1550251186000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "the Sri Lanka Accounting Standards.","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":4,"end":33,"text":"Sri Lanka Accounting Standards"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550249172000,"last_updated_at":1550249172000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Executive Deputy Chairman - Mr. J.Molligoda Chief Operating Operations - Mr. M.F.Majeed Chief Financial Officer - Mrs. C.Wahalathantri General Manager Low Country - Mr. M.A.Fernando Senior Manager Personnel/Admin - Mr. U.S.Waidyatilleke Senior Manager QA/QC - Mr. V.A.S.Panditharathne Manager Business Development - Mr. H.M.C.Gamagedara Head of Production and Exports (BTC) - Mr. N.Alwis Executive Assistant to Co-Chairman - Mr.A. Ambani Vice President Marketing - Mr. U.Perera - Mr. J.M.Ratwatte - Mr. V Wickramarathna - Mr. Y.M.T.K.Bandara General Manager Up Country - Mr. R.M.Samarakoone - Mrs. S.Rajarammohan Manager Marketing - Mr. C.S.Senavirathne Head of Monitoring - Mr. S.R.Rajapakse Vice President Operations & Finance- Mr. R.Bopage - Mr. D.Perera - K.","annotation":[{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":730,"end":741,"text":"Mr. R.Bopage"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":675,"end":691,"text":"Mr. S.R.Rajapakse"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":633,"end":652,"text":"Mr. C.S.Senavirathne"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":593,"end":611,"text":"Mrs. S.Rajarammohan"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":571,"end":589,"text":"Mr. R.M.Samarakoone"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":522,"end":540,"text":"Mr. Y.M.T.K.Bandara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":499,"end":518,"text":"Mr. V Wickramarathna"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":480,"end":495,"text":"Mr. J.M.Ratwatte"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":465,"end":476,"text":"Mr. U.Perera"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":425,"end":436,"text":"Mr.A. Ambani"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":376,"end":386,"text":"Mr. N.Alwis"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":316,"end":335,"text":"Mr. H.M.C.Gamagedara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":260,"end":283,"text":"Mr. V.A.S.Panditharathne"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":215,"end":235,"text":"Mr. U.S.Waidyatilleke"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":165,"end":180,"text":"Mr. M.A.Fernando"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":114,"end":133,"text":"Mrs. C.Wahalathantri"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":73,"end":86,"text":"Mr. M.F.Majeed"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":28,"end":42,"text":"Mr. J.Molligoda"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550253250000,"last_updated_at":1550253250000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Liyanage Chief Internal Auditor - Mr. J.M.G.Bandara Mr. S.A.I.B.Peiris Mr. K.G.Samarathunga Mr. K.S.Weerasuriya Mr. A.P.Wishwanath Mr. M.Y.B.Markar Mr. Randunne Jayathilaka Mr. N.De Alwis Mr. S.Wijewardena Mr. E.U.D.B.G.D.Ehelepola Mr. A.D.W.K.Kariyawasam Mr. H.E.Wejesundara Mr. J.R.R.Warnakulasuriya value  for  all  stakeholders.  The  Directors  confirm  that  the of the Colombo Stock Exchange.","annotation":[{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":376,"end":397,"text":"Colombo Stock Exchange"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":276,"end":300,"text":"Mr. J.R.R.Warnakulasuriya"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":256,"end":274,"text":"Mr. H.E.Wejesundara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":232,"end":254,"text":"Mr. A.D.W.K.Kariyawasam"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":206,"end":230,"text":"Mr. E.U.D.B.G.D.Ehelepola"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":188,"end":204,"text":"Mr. S.Wijewardena"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":173,"end":186,"text":"Mr. N.De Alwis"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":148,"end":171,"text":"Mr. Randunne Jayathilaka"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":131,"end":146,"text":"Mr. M.Y.B.Markar"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":112,"end":129,"text":"Mr. A.P.Wishwanath"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":92,"end":110,"text":"Mr. K.S.Weerasuriya"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":71,"end":90,"text":"Mr. K.G.Samarathunga"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":52,"end":69,"text":"Mr. S.A.I.B.Peiris"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":34,"end":50,"text":"Mr. J.M.G.Bandara"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550252822000,"last_updated_at":1550252822000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Mr. D J Ambani Mr. L J Ambani Mr. C M O Haglind Mr. D A D S Wickramanayake Mr. S A S Jayasundara expenditure  and  any  other  project  proposals.","annotation":[{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":75,"end":95,"text":"Mr. S A S Jayasundara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":48,"end":73,"text":"Mr. D A D S Wickramanayake"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":30,"end":46,"text":"Mr. C M O Haglind"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":15,"end":28,"text":"Mr. L J Ambani"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":13,"text":"Mr. D J Ambani"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550253021000,"last_updated_at":1550253021000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Directors at the Board Meetings. page no 24. within  the  Company,  to  the  Board  of  BTE  PLC.  The  Board recommendations.  The  remuneration  recommendations  are based on the present market rates.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":88,"end":95,"text":"BTE  PLC"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251571000,"last_updated_at":1550251571000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "The  Board  of  Directors requirements of the Colombo Stock Exchange.","annotation":[{"label":["NORP"],"points":[{"start":46,"end":67,"text":"Colombo Stock Exchange"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550248778000,"last_updated_at":1550248778000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "certified statements from respective operational managers. BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC - Annual Report 2017 - 2018Corporate Governance Contd. Please refer page no 30. Two of the four non-executive directors are Independent Directors. Compliant Mr.  G  V  M  Nanayakkara    and  Mr.  S  A  S the Company.  Mr. G V M Nanayakkara  and Mr.  S  A  S  Jayasundera    are  also  Directors  of Metropolitan  Resource  Holdings  PLC  (MRH). is  not  compromised.    Accordingly,  the  Board has determined that Mr. G V M Nanayakkara and  Mr.  S  A  S  Jayasundara  are  independent Please refer page no 30. Please refer page no  19. formed.","annotation":[{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":531,"end":555,"text":"Mr.  S  A  S  Jayasundara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":504,"end":524,"text":"Mr. G V M Nanayakkara"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":389,"end":424,"text":"etropolitan  Resource  Holdings  PLC"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":334,"end":358,"text":"Mr.  S  A  S  Jayasundera"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":307,"end":327,"text":"Mr. G V M Nanayakkara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":246,"end":270,"text":"Mr.  G  V  M  Nanayakkara"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":58,"end":87,"text":" BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550249987000,"last_updated_at":1550249987000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Please refer page no 32. Please refer page no 21. Please refer page no 59. A separate Audit Committee was formed. Please refer page no 32. consists of the following Non-Executive Directors. ²  Mr. G V M Nanayakkara-Chairman ²  Mr. C M O Haglind ²  Mr. S A S Jayasundara ²  Review of internal control systems.","annotation":[{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":248,"end":268,"text":"Mr. S A S Jayasundara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":227,"end":243,"text":"Mr. C M O Haglind"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":193,"end":213,"text":"Mr. G V M Nanayakkara"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550248804000,"last_updated_at":1550248804000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "with  SLFRS,  Companies  Act  No.  7  of  2007,  rules  and regulations of CSE and SEC.","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":49,"end":85,"text":"rules  and regulations of CSE and SEC"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":14,"end":45,"text":"Companies  Act  No.  7  of  2007"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":6,"end":10,"text":"SLFRS"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550249200000,"last_updated_at":1550249200000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "safeguard the assets of the company and its subsidiaries. The to the subsidiary company, Bogawantalawa Tea Ceylon Ltd. the Senior Management. The Directors review the performance held quarterly on a pre-determined dates agreed.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":89,"end":116,"text":"Bogawantalawa Tea Ceylon Ltd"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251637000,"last_updated_at":1550251637000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Mr. G V M Nanayakkara-Chairman Mr. S A S Jayasundara - Member Mr. J. Molligoda - Member CSE. The composition and the scope of work of the Committee Listing Rules.","annotation":[{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":62,"end":77,"text":"Mr. J. Molligoda"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":31,"end":51,"text":"Mr. S A S Jayasundara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":20,"text":"Mr. G V M Nanayakkara"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550248868000,"last_updated_at":1550248868000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "requirements and the Sri Lanka Accounting Standards.","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":21,"end":50,"text":"Sri Lanka Accounting Standards"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251100000,"last_updated_at":1550251100000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "and all members attended for the meetings. The quorum for a meeting is two (2) members. regularly reported to the Board of Directors. accorded to other constituents of the company. Committee Report Contd. Reference of the Committee. Colombo Stock Exchange.","annotation":[{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":233,"end":254,"text":"Colombo Stock Exchange"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550253152000,"last_updated_at":1550253152000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "March 2018. Act  No.  07  of  2007,  the  Listing  Rules  of  the  Colombo  Stock Exchange and is guided by recommended best practices. Act No.17 of 1982 as a public Company on 22nd June 1992. Pursuant to the requirements of the new Companies Act No. 7 bears registration number PQ 124.  Accordingly, the name of the Company has changed to Bogawantalawa Tea Estates PLC. request of the Board of Directors. processing of Tea and Rubber, remained unchanged.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":428,"end":433,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":420,"end":422,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":354,"end":356,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":340,"end":368,"text":"Bogawantalawa Tea Estates PLC"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":136,"end":152,"text":"Act No.17 of 1982"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":42,"end":89,"text":"Listing  Rules  of  the  Colombo  Stock Exchange"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":12,"end":33,"text":"Act  No.  07  of  2007"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251744000,"last_updated_at":1550251744000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "appear on page 19. Mr. D J Ambani Mr. L J Ambani Mr. J Molligoda Mr. C M O Haglind Mr. D A De S Wickramanayake *Mr. S A S Jayasundara *Mr. G V M Nanayakkara Mr. C M O Haglind retires by rotation at the conclusion of the the Directors for re-election. Mr.  G  V  M  Nanayakkara  who  is  over  70  years  of  age,  as  a Companies Act in regard to the re- appointment of Mr. G V M Nanayakkara.","annotation":[{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":370,"end":390,"text":"Mr. G V M Nanayakkara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":157,"end":173,"text":"Mr. C M O Haglind"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":135,"end":155,"text":"Mr. G V M Nanayakkara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":112,"end":132,"text":"Mr. S A S Jayasundara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":83,"end":109,"text":"Mr. D A De S Wickramanayake"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":65,"end":81,"text":"Mr. C M O Haglind"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":49,"end":63,"text":"Mr. J Molligoda"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":34,"end":47,"text":"Mr. L J Ambani"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":19,"end":32,"text":"Mr. D J Ambani"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550253289000,"last_updated_at":1550253289000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "The Stated Capital of the Company is Rs.586,250,010/-. as at 31st March 2018 and 31st March 2017 are as follows.","annotation":[{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":61,"end":75,"text":"31st March 2018"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550249868000,"last_updated_at":1550249868000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Mr. D J Ambani Mr. L J Ambani Mr. C M O Haglind Mr. D A de S Wickramanayake Mr. S J S Jayasundara Mr. J Molligoda Mr. G V M Nanayakkara 2018 (18,615 shareholders as at 31st March 2017). The details of distribution are given on page 17 of this Report.","annotation":[{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":114,"end":134,"text":"Mr. G V M Nanayakkara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":98,"end":112,"text":"Mr. J Molligoda"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":76,"end":96,"text":"Mr. S J S Jayasundara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":48,"end":74,"text":"Mr. D A de S Wickramanayake"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":30,"end":46,"text":"Mr. C M O Haglind"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":15,"end":28,"text":"Mr. L J Ambani"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":13,"text":"Mr. D J Ambani"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550252928000,"last_updated_at":1550252928000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Mr. G V M Nanayakkara - Chairman Mr. S A S Jayasundara - Member Mr. C M O Haglind - Member Mr. G V M Nanayakkara - Chairman Mr. S A S Jayasundara - Member Mr. C M O Haglind - Member Mr. G V M Nanayakkara - Chairman Mr. S A S Jayasundara - Member Mr. J Molligoda - Member of  policies  and  practices.","annotation":[{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":246,"end":260,"text":"Mr. J Molligoda"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":215,"end":235,"text":"Mr. S A S Jayasundara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":182,"end":202,"text":"Mr. G V M Nanayakkara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":155,"end":171,"text":"Mr. C M O Haglind"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":124,"end":144,"text":"Mr. S A S Jayasundara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":91,"end":111,"text":"Mr. G V M Nanayakkara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":64,"end":80,"text":"Mr. C M O Haglind"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":33,"end":53,"text":"Mr. S A S Jayasundara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":20,"text":"Mr. G V M Nanayakkara"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550252987000,"last_updated_at":1550252987000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Sujeewa Rajapakse FCA, FCMA.","annotation":[{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":16,"text":"Sujeewa Rajapakse"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251036000,"last_updated_at":1550251036000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Mrs. Chamari Wahalathantri The Board of Directors is responsible for the preparation of these financial statements. Approved and signed for and on behalf of the Board of Directors of Bogawantalawa Tea Estates PLC. Sgd.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":184,"end":211,"text":"ogawantalawa Tea Estates PLC"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":25,"text":"Mrs. Chamari Wahalathantri"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251557000,"last_updated_at":1550251557000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Mr. D. J. Ambani Sgd.","annotation":[{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":15,"text":"Mr. D. J. Ambani"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251314000,"last_updated_at":1550251314000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Mr. L. J.Ambani Rs. Rs. Rs. Rs. Rs. Figures in brackets indicate deductions.","annotation":[{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":14,"text":"Mr. L. J.Ambani"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550248475000,"last_updated_at":1550248475000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "The significant accounting policies and the notes from pages 39 to 90 form an integral part of these financial statements. 1.1.  Domicile and legal form in Sri Lanka, under the Companies Act No.17 of 1982 later  got  replaced  with  the  Companies  Act  No.07  of Undertakings  into  Public  Companies  Act  No.23  of 1987. The registered office of the company is located at  No.153,  Nawala  Road,  Narahenpita,  Colombo  05, Bogawantalawa and Deraniyagala.","annotation":[{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":445,"end":456,"text":"Deraniyagala"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":427,"end":439,"text":"Bogawantalawa"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":283,"end":321,"text":" Public  Companies  Act  No.23  of 1987"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":177,"end":203,"text":"Companies Act No.17 of 1982"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":156,"end":164,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251172000,"last_updated_at":1550251172000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "1.3.  Name of immediate and ultimate parent enterprise and ultimate parent company is Metrocrop (Pvt) Ltd. Holdings Limited.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":86,"end":104,"text":"Metrocrop (Pvt) Ltd"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550249892000,"last_updated_at":1550249892000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "1.4.  Date of authorization for issue for issue by the directors on 20th August, 2018. 2.1.  Statement of compliance Companies Act No.07 of 2007 and amendments thereto, Listing Rules of the Colombo Stock Exchange.","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":177,"end":211,"text":"Rules of the Colombo Stock Exchange"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550249672000,"last_updated_at":1550249672000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "2.6.  Offsetting offset unless required or permitted by SLFRSs/LKASs. 2.7.  Going concern future. Furthermore, management is not aware of any concern.","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":63,"end":66,"text":"LKAS"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":56,"end":60,"text":"SLFRS"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251665000,"last_updated_at":1550251665000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "2.8.  Responsibility for financial statements the Companies Act No. 07 of 2007 and the Sri Lanka Accounting Standards.","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":87,"end":116,"text":"Sri Lanka Accounting Standards"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":50,"end":77,"text":"Companies Act No. 07 of 2007"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550250004000,"last_updated_at":1550250004000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "3.1.  Basis of consolidation as at 31st March, 2018. Control is achieved when the affect those returns through its power over the investee.","annotation":[{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":35,"end":50,"text":"31st March, 2018"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550248459000,"last_updated_at":1550248459000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "April,  2011  in  accordance  with  provisions  of  SLFRS  1. cost less accumulated depreciation.","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":52,"end":59,"text":"SLFRS  1"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550248754000,"last_updated_at":1550248754000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Tea,  rubber,  palm biological assets.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":15,"end":18,"text":"palm"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":6,"end":11,"text":"rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":2,"text":"Tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251601000,"last_updated_at":1550251601000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "3.5.3.  Consumable biological assets timber  trees  that  are  to  be  sold  as  biological  assets.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":37,"end":49,"text":"timber  trees"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550253135000,"last_updated_at":1550253135000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "its fair value less cost to sell in terms of LKAS 41. The such plants to price during this period is immaterial.","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":45,"end":51,"text":"LKAS 41"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251771000,"last_updated_at":1550251771000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "The  Eucalyptus  Grandis they are 20 years old. Eucalyptus Grandis trees at their initial stage (i.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":48,"end":71,"text":"Eucalyptus Grandis trees"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251055000,"last_updated_at":1550251055000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "charged to the statement of comprehensive income. LKAS 23 - \"Borrowing costs\".","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":50,"end":56,"text":"LKAS 23"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251953000,"last_updated_at":1550251953000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC - Annual Report 2017 - 2018Significant Accounting Policies Contd. company and the group. The company and the group probable, but not virtually certain. minority interest. 3.20.  Deferred revenue 3.20.1. Government grants and subsidies and all attached conditions will be compiled with. When compensate.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":28,"text":"BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550249852000,"last_updated_at":1550249852000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "3.20.2. Net income from operating rights given Significant Accounting Policies Contd. with the provisions of the Inland Revenue Act. No. 10 of 2006 and subsequent amendments thereto.","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":113,"end":146,"text":"Inland Revenue Act. No. 10 of 2006"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550249647000,"last_updated_at":1550249647000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC - Annual Report 2017 - 2018Significant Accounting Policies Contd. 3.23.2. Interest interest method.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":28,"text":"BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550248525000,"last_updated_at":1550248525000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "3.27.  Related party disclosures 3.27.1. Transactions with related parties related  parties  in  Sri  Lanka  Accounting  Standard  24. customers. 3.27.2. Transactions with key management personnel entity.  Accordingly,  the  board  of  directors  (including company.","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":97,"end":128,"text":"Sri  Lanka  Accounting  Standard"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251508000,"last_updated_at":1550251508000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Rs. Rs. Rs. 10.  MANAGEMENT FEE EXPENSES - 5.15% of the previous year's total comprehensive income/(expense), net of tax upto Rs.100 million. - 7.5% of the previous year's total comprehensive income/(expense), net of tax from Rs.100 to Rs.200 million. - 9.85% of the previous year's total comprehensive income/(expense), net of tax over Rs.200 million. BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC - Annual Report 2017 - 2018Notes to the Financial Statements Contd. 11.  NET FINANCE INCOME/ (EXPENSES) Rs. Rs. Rs. 13.1  Current income tax expense Notes to the Financial Statements Contd. 13.2  Reconciliation of accounting profit/ (loss) to income tax expense Rs. Rs. Rs. 14.1  Basic earnings per ordinary share Rs. Rs. Rs. Basic earnings per ordinary share (Rs.) 14.2  Diluted earnings per ordinary share shares. There were no potentially dilutive shares outstanding at any time during the year/previous year. 15.  DIVIDEND PER SHARE Dividend paid (Rs.) No. of ordinary shares in issue (Nos.) Dividend per ordinary share (Rs.) Rs. Rs. Rs. BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC - Annual Report 2017 - 2018Notes to the Financial Statements Contd.  JEDB/SLSPC estates allocated to the company have been handed over to, and are being operated by the company. Lease deeds of all estates have been executed. All leases signed are retroactive to 22nd June,1992, the date of formation of the company. The the Institute of Chartered Accountants of Sri Lanka.","annotation":[{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":1124,"end":1141,"text":"JEDB/SLSPC estates"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":1025,"end":1053,"text":"BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":353,"end":381,"text":"BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550252674000,"last_updated_at":1550252674000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "formation. The assets taken over by way of estates leases are set out in notes 16 and 17 above. amounting to Rs.267,597,559/- (Group - Rs 317,055,028/-). Information of the freehold building of the company/group is disclosed below as required under Rule 7.6 (VIII) of the Colombo Stock Exchange listing rules.","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":272,"end":307,"text":"Colombo Stock Exchange listing rules"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550248948000,"last_updated_at":1550248948000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Square Feet  No. of Buildings Rs. 19.1.1  Cost 19.1.2  Accumulated depreciation Rs. Rs. Rs. Rs. Rs. 19.1.3  Written down value as at 31st March, 2018 19.1.4  Written down value as at 31st March, 2017 19.1.5  Brand  development  represents  the  investments  made  in  brand  developments,  acquiring  marketing  rights  and  legal protections  for  the  brands  which  will  result  in  future  economic  benefits.  Brand  acquisition  cost  has  been  amortized protection have been amortized over a period of ten years commencing from 2004/2005. BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC - Annual Report 2017 - 2018Notes to the Financial Statements Contd. Notes to the Financial Statements Contd. Note 21.1 Rs. 21.1  Biological assets at initial stage 21.2  The biological assets, Eucalyptus Grandis mature and immature timber trees of the company were inspected and valued by M/S. Ariyatileka & Co (Pvt) Ltd independent Chartered Valuers (UK) as at 31st March, 2016. Based on this valuation report, position after making adjustments for risk at individual fields to reflect the requirement of the Sri Lanka Accounting Standards.","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":1088,"end":1117,"text":"Sri Lanka Accounting Standards"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":867,"end":898,"text":"M/S. Ariyatileka & Co (Pvt) Ltd "}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":771,"end":788,"text":"Eucalyptus Grandis"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":548,"end":576,"text":"BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC"}]},{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":133,"end":148,"text":"31st March, 2018"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251842000,"last_updated_at":1550251842000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Accordingly, directors of the company have determined the fair value of these trees as Rs.839,998,276/- as at 31st March, 2018. Eucalyptus Grandis timber trees are measured at the directors' assessment of their value at each reporting date. The fair value  is  determined  as  being  the  net  present  value  of  expected  future  cash  flows  (discounted  at  a  risk  adjusted  rate).","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":128,"end":158,"text":"Eucalyptus Grandis timber trees"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251473000,"last_updated_at":1550251473000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "during the next 02 to 05 years with clear fell at 20 years. Corporation and prices of timber trees sold by estates and prices of logs and sawn timber in the popular timber traders in Sri Lanka. Future cash flows are determined by references to current timber prices without considering the inflationary effect.","annotation":[{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":183,"end":191,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":86,"end":97,"text":"timber trees"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550248597000,"last_updated_at":1550248597000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "natural forces. The company has extensive processes in place aimed at monitoring and mitigating those risks, including regular forest health inspections and industry pest and disease surveys. The company also insures itself against natural disasters such as floods, land slides and hurricanes. 21.4  Sensitivity analysis 21.4.1 Sensitivity variation on sales price changes into the average sales prices applied. Simulations made for timber show that an increase or decrease by 10% of (Rs.) (Rs.) (Rs.) 21.4.2 Sensitivity variation on discount rate of the discount rate applied. Simulations made for timber show that an increase or decrease by 1 % of the estimated future (Rs.) (Rs.) (Rs.) Rs. Notes to the Financial Statements Contd. Rs. Rs. Rs. (12,660,000 ordinary shares of Rs.10/- each) 23.1.1 Impairment of investments in subsidiaries amount of investment of Rs.126,600,000/- and as such the difference between the carrying amount and the recoverable amount of Rs.94,950,000/- has been recognized in the financial statements as impairment loss in the year 2008/2009. the total investment in the year 2013/2014. Accordingly, impairment provision of Rs. 31,650,000/- has been reversed to the statement of comprehensive income during the financial year 2013/2014. i. The business activities of Bogawantalawa Tea Ceylon (Pvt) Ltd, will be drastically improved in the near future. ii.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":1296,"end":1329,"text":"Bogawantalawa Tea Ceylon (Pvt) Ltd"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251257000,"last_updated_at":1550251257000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Impairment is assumed to be limited to 50% of the investment made. (1,500,000 ordinary shares of Rs.10/- each) Rs. Rs. Rs. The company has received 1,500,000 ordinary shares of Rs.10/- each free of charge from Tea Trails (Pvt) Ltd, as promoter shares. Corresponding entry has been credited to the income statement in the year 2005/2006. 24.  DEFERRED TAX ASSETS Rs. 24.1  Deferred tax and the resultant tax effect is disclosed in year 2016/2017. However, deferred tax assets for the year have been recognised probable that these assets will be recovered.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":210,"end":229,"text":"Tea Trails (Pvt) Ltd"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550249764000,"last_updated_at":1550249764000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Notes to the Financial Statements Contd. Notes to the Financial Statements Contd. TRADE AND OTHER RECEIVABLES (Contd...) Rs. Rs. Rs. Rs. Rs. Rs. Rs. Rs. Rs. Rs. Rs. Rs. Rs. BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC - Annual Report 2017 - 2018Notes to the Financial Statements Contd. 29.1  Favourable balances Rs. Rs. Rs. Nos. Nos. 29.2  Unfavourable balances 30.1  Number of shares No. of ordinary shares including one golden share held by the Treasury which has special rights 30.2  Value of shares Rs. 30.3  The golden shareholder of Sri Lanka or by a 100% Government owned public company. In addition to the rights of the normal ordinary shareholders, in terms of the articles of the company, following special rights are vested with the golden shareholder. its rights in part or all of the land leased/to be leased to the company by the JEDB/SLSPC. his nominee to discuss matters of the company to the state. giving two weeks written notice to the company. golden shareholder and the company. to the company in a pre-specified format agreed to by the golden shareholder and the company. Notes to the Financial Statements Contd. BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC - Annual Report 2017 - 2018Notes to the Financial Statements Contd. Notes to the Financial Statements Contd. BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC - Annual Report 2017 - 2018Notes to the Financial Statements Contd. Notes to the Financial Statements Contd. BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC - Annual Report 2017 - 2018Notes to the Financial Statements Contd. Notes to the Financial Statements Contd. Provision for the year                                Note 33.1 Rs. Rs. Rs. 33.1  Expenses recognized in the statement of comprehensive income and other comprehensive income for the year ended 31st March, 2018. Rs. Rs. Rs. 33.2  Provision for gratuity for the financial year 2017/2018 has been determined based on the latest actuarial valuation report issued  on  28/05/2018  which  was  done  by  Actuarial  &  Management  Consultants  (Pvt)  Ltd.  The  provision  in  respect  of gratuity liabilities of existing employees as at 31st March, 2018 is Rs. 631,237,454/- (company). If the company had provided payment of Gratuities Act No. 12 of 1983, the liability would have been Rs. 726,349,480/-. Hence, there is a contingent liability of Rs. 95,112,026/- which would crystallize only if the company ceases to be a going concern. 33.3  The key assumptions used by the actuary are disclosed in the note 3.17.1 to the financial statements. 33.4  Sensitivity analysis   Benefit Obligation (Rs.) 33.5  Even though the group policy for recognizing the gratuity provision is the actuarial valuation, Bogawantalawa Tea Ceylon method. However, the effect for not applying the actuarial valuation (subsidiary) is not material to the group as at the date of the statement of financial position.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":2633,"end":2656,"text":"Bogawantalawa Tea Ceylon"}]},{"label":["MONEY"],"points":[{"start":2217,"end":2233,"text":"Rs. 726,349,480/-"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":2156,"end":2184,"text":"Gratuities Act No. 12 of 1983"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":1398,"end":1426,"text":"BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":1259,"end":1287,"text":"BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":1120,"end":1148,"text":"BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":524,"end":532,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":173,"end":201,"text":"BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550249345000,"last_updated_at":1550249345000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC - Annual Report 2017 - 2018Notes to the Financial Statements Contd. 35.  DEFERRED INCOME - (GROUP/COMPANY) Net income from operating rights given to Lalan Rubbers (Pvt) Ltd       35.1 35.1  Net income from operating rights given to Lalan Rubbers (Pvt) Ltd 36.  NET LIABILITY TO LESSOR OF JEDB/SLSPC ESTATES - (GROUP/COMPANY) 36.1  Gross liability 36.2  Finance charges allocated to future periods 36.3  Net liability at the end of the year 36.4  Maturity analysis 36.4.1 Amount payable within one year 36.4.2 Amount payable after one year and less than five years 36.4.3 Amount payable after five years Rs. 36.4.4 Net liability payable after one year shown under non-current liabilities 36.4.5 Total net liability 36.4.6 The contingent rental of Rs. 60,570,410/- has been recovered from Lalan Rubber (Pvt) Ltd, and Walters Bay Tea Estates (Pvt) Ltd as per operating agreements entered into with parties concerned and balance contingent rental of Rs. 19,316,848/- has been charged to the statement of comprehensive income during the year and is based on GDP deflator of 5.1% . 36.4.7 The Statement of Recommended Practice (SoRP) for right-to-use of land on lease was approved by the Council of the Institute of Chartered Accounts of Sri Lanka on 19th December, 2012. Subsequently, the amendments to the SoRP along August, 2013. The company has not reassessed the right-to-use of land since this is not a mandatory requirement. However, The above reassessed liability is not reflected in these financial statements. Notes to the Financial Statements Contd. 37.  DEFERRED TAX LIABILITY Rs. Rs. Rs. and the resultant tax effect is disclosed in year 2016/2017. by the end of the reporting period. In accordance with the Inland Revenue Act No 24 of 2017 effective from 01st April 2018, the Company has used 14% in assessing the deferred tax liability for the current financial year. Payable to bolted workers           Note 38.1 38.1  Payable to bolted workers Rs. Rs. Rs. Rs. 40.1  Contingent liabilities than those disclosed in the note 33.2 to the financial statements and circumstances disclosed below: US $ 1,685,000/- and Rs.25,000,000/- to Commercial Bank of Ceylon PLC. As per the assessment (dated 11.06.2012) issued to the company by the Department of Inland Revenue amounting to Rs.20.5Mn additional VAT liability would crystallize. The tax appeal no. TAC/VAT/04/2014 has been made by the company and awaiting for final determination from Tax Appeal Commission. 40.2  Contingent assets There were no contingent assets as at the reporting date. Notes to the Financial Statements Contd. for, outstanding as at the date of the statement of financial position.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":2171,"end":2199,"text":"Commercial Bank of Ceylon PLC"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":1745,"end":1776,"text":"Inland Revenue Act No 24 of 2017"}]},{"label":["NORP"],"points":[{"start":1227,"end":1270,"text":"Institute of Chartered Accounts of Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":845,"end":877,"text":"Walters Bay Tea Estates (Pvt) Ltd"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":817,"end":838,"text":"Lalan Rubber (Pvt) Ltd"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":262,"end":285,"text":"Lalan Rubbers (Pvt) Ltd "}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":179,"end":202,"text":"Lalan Rubbers (Pvt) Ltd "}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":28,"text":"BOGAWANTALAWA TEA ESTATES PLC"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550249527000,"last_updated_at":1550249527000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "The company is a subsidiary of Metropolitan Resource Holdings Limited, which holds 67.35% of ordinary shares of the company. In the opinion of the directors, the company's ultimate parent company as at the date of the statement of financial position is Metrocorp (Pvt) Ltd. such related companies during the year. The transactions listed below have been carried out under normal commercial terms. Mr. D. J. Ambani, Mr. C. M. O. Haglind, Mr. L. J. Ambani, Mr. S. A. S. Jayasundara and Mr. J. Molligoda, the directors of the company are also directors of the following companies and have had transactions as disclosed in the note 42.3.1 below. The company has a related party relationship with its related group companies as disclosed below. The following transactions have been carried out with related parties during the year ended 31st March, 2018 under normal commercial terms. 42.3.1  Transactions with companies in which directors of the company hold other directorships Metrocorp (Pvt) Ltd (MPL)  Mr. D. J. Ambani Holdings Limited (MRH)  Mr.D.J. Ambani Mr. L.J.Ambani Mr.C.M.O.Haglind Mr.S.A.S.Jayasundara Mr. J. Molligoda 42.3.1.1 Transactions with immediate parent company and ultimate parent company 42.3.1.2 Transactions with other related companies Ceylon (Pvt) Limited (BTC)  Mr. D. J. Ambani Mr. C.M.O. Haglind Mr. L. J. Ambani Mr. J. Molligoda Mr. D. J. Ambani Mr. L. J. Ambani Mr. L. J. Ambani company on behalf of MRH. company on behalf of ONL.","annotation":[{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1391,"end":1406,"text":"Mr. L. J. Ambani"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1374,"end":1389,"text":"Mr. L. J. Ambani"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1357,"end":1372,"text":"Mr. D. J. Ambani"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1340,"end":1355,"text":"Mr. J. Molligoda"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1323,"end":1338,"text":"Mr. L. J. Ambani"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1304,"end":1321,"text":"Mr. C.M.O. Haglind"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1287,"end":1302,"text":"Mr. D. J. Ambani"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1111,"end":1126,"text":"Mr. J. Molligoda"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1090,"end":1109,"text":"Mr.S.A.S.Jayasundara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1073,"end":1088,"text":"Mr.C.M.O.Haglind"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1058,"end":1071,"text":"Mr. L.J.Ambani"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1043,"end":1056,"text":"Mr.D.J. Ambani"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1002,"end":1017,"text":"Mr. D. J. Ambani"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":975,"end":994,"text":"Metrocorp (Pvt) Ltd "}]},{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":832,"end":847,"text":"31st March, 2018"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":484,"end":499,"text":"Mr. J. Molligoda"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":455,"end":478,"text":"Mr. S. A. S. Jayasundara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":437,"end":452,"text":"Mr. L. J. Ambani"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":415,"end":434,"text":"Mr. C. M. O. Haglind"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":397,"end":412,"text":"Mr. D. J. Ambani"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":253,"end":272,"text":"Metrocorp (Pvt) Ltd."}]},{"label":["PERCENT"],"points":[{"start":83,"end":88,"text":"67.35%"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":31,"end":68,"text":"Metropolitan Resource Holdings Limited"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550248726000,"last_updated_at":1550248726000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "of expenses made by the company. Expenses incurred by the company. 1,685,000 and Rs. 25,000,000/- to Commercial Bank of Ceylon PLC.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":101,"end":129,"text":"Commercial Bank of Ceylon PLC"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550249361000,"last_updated_at":1550249361000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Rs. Rs. Notes to the Financial Statements Contd. 42.3.1.2 Transactions with Other Related Companies (Contd…) Tea Trails (Pvt) Ltd (TTPL) Mr. D. J. Ambani Mr. D. J. Ambani Mr. L. J. Ambani 42.3.1.3 Subsidiary - Bogawantalawa Tea Ceylon (Pvt) Ltd Mr. D. J. Ambani Mr. L. J. Ambani Mr. C. M. O. Haglind Mr. J. Molligoda Estates (Pvt) Ltd (WBTE)  Mr. D. J. Ambani Mr. J. Molligoda Mr. D. J. Ambani Mr. J. Molligoda Rs. Rs. 42.3.2  Transactions with Key Management Personnel (KMP) of the Company or Parent or otherwise) of the company. No loans have been given to the directors of the company and its parent company. Rs. Rs. Rs. managerial personnel during the year. 42.3.3 Amounts receivable and payable to related parties are disclosed in the notes 28 and 39 to the financial statements. Notes to the Financial Statements Contd. 43.  OPERATING AGREEMENT WITH LALAN RUBBERS (PVT) LTD  The company has entered into an operating agreement (OA) with Lalan Rubbers (Pvt) Ltd., (LRL) effective from 19th March, 2003 whereby LRL will operate and manage the rubber division of the company from 01st April, 2003. Consequently, LRL obtained by the division from that date.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":943,"end":966,"text":"Lalan Rubbers (Pvt) Ltd."}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":856,"end":878,"text":"LALAN RUBBERS (PVT) LTD"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":394,"end":409,"text":"Mr. J. Molligoda"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":377,"end":392,"text":"Mr. D. J. Ambani"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":360,"end":375,"text":"Mr. J. Molligoda"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":343,"end":358,"text":"Mr. D. J. Ambani"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":300,"end":315,"text":"Mr. J. Molligoda"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":279,"end":298,"text":"Mr. C. M. O. Haglind"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":262,"end":277,"text":"Mr. L. J. Ambani"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":245,"end":260,"text":"Mr. D. J. Ambani"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":210,"end":243,"text":"Bogawantalawa Tea Ceylon (Pvt) Ltd"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":171,"end":186,"text":"Mr. L. J. Ambani"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":154,"end":169,"text":"Mr. D. J. Ambani"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":137,"end":152,"text":"Mr. D. J. Ambani"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":109,"end":128,"text":"Tea Trails (Pvt) Ltd"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550253115000,"last_updated_at":1550253115000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "As per the terms of the operating agreement a payment of approximately Rs 278.25 million has been made by LRL to Bogawantalawa Tea Estates PLC (BTE PLC) in consideration for the operating rights obtained and of which Rs.120 million has been received in the year 2002/2003. Balance payment was received in three instalments of Rs. 52.75 million each during the year, 2004, 2005 and 2006 respectively.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":113,"end":141,"text":"Bogawantalawa Tea Estates PLC"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550252732000,"last_updated_at":1550252732000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "LRL  has  also  taken  over  the  retiring  gratuity  liability  of  employees  of  the  rubber  division  estimated  at  Rs.46.8  million (at actuarial value), the capital and future interest payments of the long term loans of Rs.105.3 million  payable to the Commercial Bank of Sri Lanka and 48.21 % of the future annual land lease payments that are required to be made by BTE these leases expire. Accordingly, the retiring gratuity liability of Rs.46.8 million and the long term loans of Rs.105.3 million pay these liabilities on behalf of the company. The Secretary, Ministry of Plantation Industries (letter Ref. MP1/9/2/6/9 BPL/SL dated 10th February, 2010 addressed to approval of the golden shareholder. Accordingly, the company has entered into a sublease agreement with Lalan Rubbers (Pvt) Ltd on 12th February, 2010, and a further payment of Rs. 110 million has been made by Lalan Rubbers (Pvt) Ltd to the company. However, all the assets and liabilities pertaining to those estates subleased to Lalan Rubbers (Pvt) Ltd continue to be reflected in the books of the company (other than gratuity liability) as this is considered an operating lease. based on a MOU during the financial year of 2012/2013 as described below.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":1007,"end":1029,"text":"Lalan Rubbers (Pvt) Ltd"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":886,"end":908,"text":"Lalan Rubbers (Pvt) Ltd"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":780,"end":802,"text":"Lalan Rubbers (Pvt) Ltd"}]},{"label":["NORP"],"points":[{"start":571,"end":603,"text":"Ministry of Plantation Industries"}]},{"label":["MONEY"],"points":[{"start":491,"end":506,"text":"Rs.105.3 million"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":261,"end":288,"text":"Commercial Bank of Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["MONEY"],"points":[{"start":228,"end":243,"text":"Rs.105.3 million"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550252009000,"last_updated_at":1550252009000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "However, still the approval from the golden shareholder has not been received in this regard as at the date of the statement of financial position. hectares comprising Anhettigama, Miyanawita and Maliboda estates. Consequently, LRL will be responsible for all day to day operations of the properties.","annotation":[{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":196,"end":211,"text":"Maliboda estates"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":196,"end":203,"text":"Maliboda"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":181,"end":190,"text":"Miyanawita"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":168,"end":178,"text":"Anhettigama"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550248514000,"last_updated_at":1550248514000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "However, all the movable assets in the properties shall remain the property of BTE PLC. three hundred and sixty six million (Rs. 366,000,000/-) for the purpose of developing the properties by tea/rubber replanting, tea/rubber new planting and undertaking agricultural programs according to the initial plan.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":219,"end":224,"text":"rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":215,"end":217,"text":"tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":196,"end":201,"text":"rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":192,"end":194,"text":"tea"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":79,"end":85,"text":"BTE PLC"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251397000,"last_updated_at":1550251397000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Notes to the Financial Statements Contd. 44.  OPERATING AGREEMENT WITH WALTERS BAY TEA ESTATES (PVT) LTD (BTE PLC) and Walters Bay Tea Estates, LLC (WBTE US) and Walters Bay Tea Estates (Pvt) Ltd (WBTE SL). WBTE SL is a fully owned subsidiary of WBTES US.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":162,"end":194,"text":"Walters Bay Tea Estates (Pvt) Ltd"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":162,"end":184,"text":"Walters Bay Tea Estates"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":119,"end":141,"text":"Walters Bay Tea Estates"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":71,"end":103,"text":"WALTERS BAY TEA ESTATES (PVT) LTD"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550252494000,"last_updated_at":1550252494000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "During the financial year 2015/2016, WBTE SL handed back 456.44 hectares of Maliboda estate to BTE PLC on 16th December, 2015 and Sapumalkande tea factory was handed back on 30th December, 2015. PLC (BTE PLC) and Walters Bay Tea Estates, LLC (WBTE US) and Walters Bay Tea Estates (Pvt) Ltd (WBTE SL). According factory consisting 120.18 ha. 45.1  There have been no material events occurring after the date of the statement of financial position that require adjustments or disclosures in the financial statements.","annotation":[{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":256,"end":278,"text":"Walters Bay Tea Estates"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":213,"end":235,"text":"Walters Bay Tea Estates"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":200,"end":206,"text":"BTE PLC"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":143,"end":145,"text":"tea"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":130,"end":153,"text":"Sapumalkande tea factory"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":95,"end":101,"text":"BTE PLC"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":76,"end":90,"text":"Maliboda estate"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550252868000,"last_updated_at":1550252868000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "48.1  Company at 31.03.2018 two estates namely Loinorn and Bogawantalawa. Fettereso estates and all movable and immovable assets.","annotation":[{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":74,"end":90,"text":"Fettereso estates"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":59,"end":71,"text":"Bogawantalawa"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":47,"end":53,"text":"Loinorn"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550252077000,"last_updated_at":1550252077000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Bogawana estate.","annotation":[{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":14,"text":"Bogawana estate"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550253036000,"last_updated_at":1550253036000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "/ Nuts) Net Asset Value per Share (Rs.) Company Registration No. : PQ 124 Mr. D J Ambani ( Co-Chairman) No 3/17, Kynsey Road, Colombo 08. Fax : 4 740 588 E mail : pwcs@pwcs.","annotation":[{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":126,"end":135,"text":"Colombo 08"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":74,"end":87,"text":"Mr. D J Ambani"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550251537000,"last_updated_at":1550251537000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "lk Colombo 2. I/We the undersigned ...........................................................................................................................……....NIC No…............................................................... of .","annotation":[{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":3,"end":11,"text":"Colombo 2"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550248548000,"last_updated_at":1550248548000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "............................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................... Mr. Dinesh Jamnadas Ambani Mr. Lalithkumar Jamnadas Ambani Mr. Carl Michael Oscarsson Haglind Mr. Don Ariyaseela De Silva Wickramanayake Mr. Sudath Ajitha Samaradivakara Jayasundara Mr. Jayampathi Molligoda Mr. Gerard Victor Maurice Nanayakkara ..............................................................................................  of  …………….…………………………………………………………………………………….………………………, To re-elect Mr. C M O Haglind who retires in terms of Article No. 89 & 90 of the Articles of Association of the Company, as a Director. Mr. G V M Nanayakkara who is over 70 years of age, as a Director of year.","annotation":[{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":787,"end":807,"text":"Mr. G V M Nanayakkara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":663,"end":679,"text":"Mr. C M O Haglind"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":463,"end":499,"text":"Mr. Gerard Victor Maurice Nanayakkara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":438,"end":461,"text":"Mr. Jayampathi Molligoda"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":393,"end":436,"text":"Mr. Sudath Ajitha Samaradivakara Jayasundara"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":350,"end":391,"text":"Mr. Don Ariyaseela De Silva Wickramanayake"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":315,"end":330,"text":"Mr. Carl Michael"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":283,"end":313,"text":"Mr. Lalithkumar Jamnadas Ambani"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":256,"end":281,"text":"Mr. Dinesh Jamnadas Ambani"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550252572000,"last_updated_at":1550252572000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
