{"content": "Corporate Overview, Report Proﬁle, Revenue Distribution Local & Global, Our Land, Our Spread, Corporate Proﬁle, Milestones, Board of Directors, Corporate Management Proﬁle, Highlights for 2017/18,   Financial Highlights,   Non Financial Highlights,   Awards and Accolades,   Chairman’s Message,   Managing Director’s Message, Strategy and Focus,   Stakeholder Engagement,   Materiality Assessment,   Creating Value for our Stakeholders, Business Reviews,   Sector Reviews, Capital Management Reports,   Financial Capital,   Statement of Value Addition and Distribution,   Manufactured Capital,   Human Capital,   Social and Relationship Capital,   Natural Capital, Intellectual Capital, Governance and Risk,   GRI Index Table,   Corporate Governance,   Risk Management,   Annual Report of the Board of Directors,   Directors’ Statement on Internal Controls,   on the Affairs of the Company, Financial Reports,   Financial Calender,   Statement of Directors’ Responsibilities,   Audit Committee Report,   Related Party Transactions Review,       Committee Report,   Managing Director’s and Chief Financial,   Statement of Proﬁt or Loss,   Statement of Comprehensive Income,   Statement of Financial Position,   Statement of Changes in Equity,   Statement of Cash Flows,   Notes to the Financial Statements,   Ofﬁcer’s Responsibility Statement, Independent Auditors’ Report, Annexures,   Ten Year Summary, Investor Information,   Environmental Calculations,   Glossary,   Notice of Meeting,   Form of Proxy,   Notes,   Corporate Information, KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, Report Profile, GRI 102-10,50,51,52,53,54, This is Kelani Valley Plantations PLC’s, (KVPL) 05th Integrated Annual Report and, has been prepared in order to provide all, stakeholders with a balanced assessment, of the Company’s ability to create and, sustain value in the short-, medium- and, long-term.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":1645,"end":1675,"text":"Kelani Valley Plantations PLC’s"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548101228000,"last_updated_at":1548101228000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "The report covers the operations of KVPL, and its subsidiaries for the period 1 April, 2017 to 31 March 2018 and where relevant, is supported by comparable data relating, to the previous year.","annotation":[{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":95,"end":107,"text":"31 March 2018"}]},{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":78,"end":90,"text":"1 April, 2017"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550092992000,"last_updated_at":1550092992000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "REPORTING STANDARDS/, GUIDELINES/ FRAMEWORKS, (cid:138)(cid:3) Sri Lanka Accounting Standards, issued by The Institute of Chartered, Accountants of Sri Lanka;, (cid:138)(cid:3) Companies Act No. 07 of 2007; (cid:138)(cid:3) Sri Lanka Accounting and Auditing, (cid:138)(cid:3), Standards Act No. 15 of 1995; Listing Rules of the Colombo Stock, Exchange;, (cid:138)(cid:3) Code of Best Practice on, Corporate Governance 2017, issued by the Institute of Chartered, Accountants of Sri Lanka, (cid:138)(cid:3) Code of Best Practices on Related, (cid:138)(cid:3), Party Transactions issued by, the Securities and Exchange, Commission of Sri Lanka.","annotation":[{"label":["NORP"],"points":[{"start":592,"end":639,"text":"Securities and Exchange, Commission of Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["NORP"],"points":[{"start":438,"end":485,"text":"Institute of Chartered, Accountants of Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":371,"end":421,"text":"Code of Best Practice on, Corporate Governance 2017"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":307,"end":350,"text":"Listing Rules of the Colombo Stock, Exchange"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":224,"end":304,"text":"Sri Lanka Accounting and Auditing, (cid:138)(cid:3), Standards Act No. 15 of 1995"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":177,"end":204,"text":"Companies Act No. 07 of 2007"}]},{"label":["NORP"],"points":[{"start":109,"end":156,"text":"Institute of Chartered, Accountants of Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":63,"end":92,"text":"Sri Lanka Accounting Standards"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550240934000,"last_updated_at":1550240934000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "International Integrated Reporting, Council’s (IIRC) “Six Capitals”, Integrated Reporting < IR>, Framework, (cid:138)(cid:3) GRI Reporting Standards, (cid:138)(cid:3) UN Sustainability Development, Goals (SDG’s), (cid:138)(cid:3) United Nations Global Compact, Principles, INQUIRIES AND FEEDBACK, We will be pleased to answer any, questions and provide any clariﬁcation, on this report.","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":230,"end":270,"text":"United Nations Global Compact, Principles"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":167,"end":209,"text":"UN Sustainability Development, Goals (SDG’s"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":105,"text":"International Integrated Reporting, Council’s (IIRC) “Six Capitals”, Integrated Reporting < IR>, Framework"}]},{"label":["NORP"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":42,"text":"International Integrated Reporting, Council"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548100568000,"last_updated_at":1548100568000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Continent, America, Europe, Middle East, Africa, Asia, Russian Federation, Australia, Total Foreign Revenue, Total Local Revenue, Total Revenue, Percentage, KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, Russian Federation, Europe, Middle East, Asia, Sri Lanka, Africa, Australia, Rs. 336 Million Rubber Export Revenue.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":304,"end":309,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":303,"end":324,"text":" Rubber Export Revenue"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":277,"end":285,"text":"Australia"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":269,"end":274,"text":"Africa"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":258,"end":266,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":252,"end":255,"text":"Asia"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":239,"end":249,"text":"Middle East"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":231,"end":236,"text":"Europe"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":211,"end":228,"text":"Russian Federation"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":75,"end":83,"text":"Australia"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":55,"end":72,"text":"Russian Federation"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":49,"end":52,"text":"Asia"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":41,"end":46,"text":"Africa"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":28,"end":38,"text":"Middle East"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":20,"end":25,"text":"Europe"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":11,"end":17,"text":"America"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550061274000,"last_updated_at":1550061274000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, Our Land, GRI 102-06, Estate, 1)  Pedro, 2)   Nuwara Eliya, 3)   Glassaugh, 4)   Uda Radella, 5)   Edinburgh, 6)   Oliphant, Ingestre, 8)   Fordyce, 9)   Annﬁeld, 10)  Tillyrie, 11)  Invery, 12)  Robgill, 13)  Battalgalla, 14)  Halgolla, 15)  Ederapolla, 16)  Kitulgala, 17)  Kalupahana, 18)  Kelani, 19)  Dewalakande, 20)  Panawatte, 21)  Urumiwella, 22)  Kiriporuwa, 23)  Lavant, 24)  Ganapalla, 25)  We Oya/Polatagama, Total, Extent (Ha), Tea  Rubber, Other, crop, Other, Total, No. of  Elevation (ft), Factory, Crop,   Kgs’000  Kgs’000, Tea  Rubber, 13,128  Ha, Total Hectares Managed, 3,501Ha, 4,501Ha, Rubber, 5,126Ha, Other, Our Spread, Distribution of Land, Rubber, Other, Avissawella, KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, Kegalla, Nawalapitiya, Nuwara Eliya, 6,468 Ha, Mature, 2,267 Ha, Immature, 3,336 Ha, 2,701Ha, Rubber, 431 Ha, Other, 165Ha, 1,800 Ha, Rubber, 306 Ha, Other, KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, Corporate Profile, GRI 102-02,15, Established in 1992, Kelani Valley, Plantations PLC (KVPL) was listed on, the main board of the Colombo Stock, exchange in 1996. Celebrating its 25th year in 2017, KVPL, today is among the leading manufacturers, of Tea and Rubber. The Company owns and manages 25 estates covering over, 13,000 hectares of Tea and Rubber, plantations. More recently the Company has invested heavily to increase its footprint, through the cultivation of cinnamon on a, commercial scale, a strategy that has met, with considerable success.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":1482,"end":1489,"text":"cinnamon"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":1360,"end":1365,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":1352,"end":1354,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":1270,"end":1275,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":1262,"end":1264,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":1143,"end":1165,"text":"Colombo Stock, exchange"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":1068,"end":1073,"text":"Kelani"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":959,"end":987,"text":"KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":936,"end":941,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":896,"end":901,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":825,"end":836,"text":"Nuwara Eliya"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":811,"end":822,"text":"Nawalapitiya"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":802,"end":808,"text":"Kegalla"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":748,"end":776,"text":"KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":735,"end":745,"text":"Avissawella"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":720,"end":725,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":662,"end":667,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":600,"end":605,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":595,"end":597,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":501,"end":506,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":496,"end":498,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":457,"end":473,"text":"We Oya/Polatagama"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":441,"end":449,"text":"Ganapalla"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":428,"end":433,"text":"Lavant"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":410,"end":420,"text":" Kiriporuwa"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":394,"end":403,"text":"Urumiwella"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":378,"end":386,"text":"Panawatte"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":360,"end":370,"text":"Dewalakande"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":347,"end":352,"text":"Kelani"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":330,"end":339,"text":"Kalupahana"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":314,"end":322,"text":"Kitulgala"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":297,"end":306,"text":"Ederapolla"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":282,"end":289,"text":"Halgolla"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":264,"end":274,"text":"Battalgalla"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":250,"end":256,"text":"Robgill"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":237,"end":242,"text":"Invery"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":222,"end":229,"text":"Tillyrie"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":208,"end":214,"text":"Annﬁeld"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":194,"end":200,"text":"Fordyce"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":169,"end":176,"text":"Oliphant"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":153,"end":161,"text":"Edinburgh"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":135,"end":145,"text":"Uda Radella"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":119,"end":127,"text":"Glassaugh"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":100,"end":111,"text":"Nuwara Eliya"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":88,"end":92,"text":"Pedro"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":28,"text":"KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550238925000,"last_updated_at":1550238925000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "KVPL owns and operates 11 ISO 22000;, 2005 Certiﬁed factories, which manufacture, the highest-quality Pure Ceylon Tea for the, global market. In addition, the Company’s Glassaugh factory produces green Tea also, for the export market, while KVPL’s Nuwara, Eliya factory specialises in the production, of instant Tea for the local market and, Hayleys Global Beverages (Pvt) Ltd. The state of the art Tea extract plant in Hatton, caters to the international market. KVPL’s two Tea centres – the Pedro Estate Ethical, Tea Boutique in Nuwara Eliya as well as the, newly-launched “Tea Train” at Edinburgh, Estate in Nanuoya, add considerable brand, value to KVPL’s credentials as a leading Tea, manufacturer in the country.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":685,"end":687,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":611,"end":617,"text":"Nanuoya"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":590,"end":606,"text":"Edinburgh, Estate"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":576,"end":578,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":575,"end":606,"text":"“Tea Train” at Edinburgh, Estate"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":531,"end":542,"text":"Nuwara Eliya"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":515,"end":517,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":493,"end":526,"text":"Pedro Estate Ethical, Tea Boutique"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":475,"end":477,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":420,"end":425,"text":"Hatton"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":399,"end":401,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":342,"end":376,"text":"Hayleys Global Beverages (Pvt) Ltd."}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":312,"end":314,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":304,"end":314,"text":"instant Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":248,"end":260,"text":"Nuwara, Eliya"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":202,"end":204,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":196,"end":204,"text":"green Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":114,"end":116,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":107,"end":116,"text":"Ceylon Tea"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":26,"end":41,"text":"ISO 22000;, 2005"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550092472000,"last_updated_at":1550092472000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "KVPL is also one of the leading RA–FSC, Certiﬁed Rubber producers in Sri, Lanka. The Company’s two factories in Yatiyantota and Dehiowita produce, sole crepe, centrifuge latex and crepe, Rubber used mainly as raw material in the, manufacture of Rubber gloves and for the, pharmaceutical and shoe industries.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":245,"end":250,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":187,"end":192,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":180,"end":184,"text":"crepe"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":159,"end":174,"text":"centrifuge latex"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":152,"end":156,"text":"crepe"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":128,"end":136,"text":"Dehiowita"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":112,"end":122,"text":"Yatiyantota"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":69,"end":78,"text":"Sri, Lanka"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":49,"end":54,"text":"Rubber"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550244640000,"last_updated_at":1550244640000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "In addition to its core business in the, manufacture of Tea and Rubber, the, Company has been steadily diversifying, into other complementary business, models, including marketing of value-, added and specialty Teas via Mabroc, Teas (Pvt) Ltd., acquired in 2010, and in hydro power by way of Kalupahana Power, Company (Pvt) Ltd., established in 2003 . The most recent addition to KVPL’s, portfolio of businesses is Kelani Valley, Resorts (Pvt) Ltd. (KVR), which was formed in 2016 to mark KVPL’s entry, into the leisure sector in Sri Lanka.","annotation":[{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":530,"end":538,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":489,"end":492,"text":"KVPL"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":415,"end":448,"text":"Kelani Valley, Resorts (Pvt) Ltd. "}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":380,"end":383,"text":"KVPL"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":292,"end":327,"text":"Kalupahana Power, Company (Pvt) Ltd."}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":270,"end":280,"text":"hydro power"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":228,"end":230,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":220,"end":242,"text":"Mabroc, Teas (Pvt) Ltd."}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":211,"end":213,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":64,"end":69,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":56,"end":58,"text":"Tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550213795000,"last_updated_at":1550213795000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "The Oliphant Estate Bungalow in Nuwara, Eliya was renovated into a luxury, boutique hotel and brought under KVR.","annotation":[{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":32,"end":44,"text":"Nuwara, Eliya"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":4,"end":27,"text":"Oliphant Estate Bungalow"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550245838000,"last_updated_at":1550245838000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "The Oliphant Boutique Bungalow is, situated 7,600 feet above sea level and, located in the picturesque Nuwara Eliya, region, in Shanthipura, a village that sits, at the highest elevation in the island.","annotation":[{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":128,"end":138,"text":"Shanthipura"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":103,"end":114,"text":"Nuwara Eliya"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":4,"end":29,"text":"Oliphant Boutique Bungalow"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550211691000,"last_updated_at":1550211691000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Surrounded by the lush Tea plantations of, the Oliphant estate, the bungalow offers, visitors a unique value proposition by, way of a truly colonial experience amidst, breathtaking vistas of lush greenery.","annotation":[{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":47,"end":61,"text":"Oliphant estate"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":23,"end":37,"text":"Tea plantations"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550063436000,"last_updated_at":1550063436000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "We are aware of the changing environment and, contribute towards enhancing the quality, of life for a better Sri Lanka and a better, world.","annotation":[{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":109,"end":117,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548143276000,"last_updated_at":1548143276000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "A.P. Certiﬁcation Black Tea factory at, Glassaugh converted to, green Tea, Acquired balance, 5% of Kelani, Valley Instant Tea, (Pvt) Ltd. Incorporation of, Hayleys Global, Beverages (Pvt), Limited and invested, on 51% ownership of, shares, Rainforest, Alliance, certiﬁcation, Celebration of 25 years, in the plantation industry,, excellence in Tea and, Rubber plantations, Acquired balance, 60% of Mabroc, Teas (Pvt) Ltd. Commenced, operations of, Kalupahana, Power Company, (Pvt) Ltd. UN Global Compact, Signatory with, Mabroc and KVPL, Ownership of, HGBL reduced, to 40% from, 51% with effect, from 31 March, 2016 due to, new allotment of, shares, Incorporation of fully-owned, subsidiary Kelani Valley Resorts, (Pvt) Ltd. Highest ever recognition of, National  Business Excellence, Awards 2017 by winning the, overall  Excellence Bronze, Award with six Gold Awards and, two Silver Awards, KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, Board of Directors, KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, Board of Directors Contd. 01.  A M Pandithage Chairman/Executive Director, 03.  S Siriwardana Chief Executive Officer/Executive Director, Chairman and Chief Executive of Hayleys PLC.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":1244,"end":1255,"text":"Hayleys PLC."}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1154,"end":1166,"text":"S Siriwardana"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1105,"end":1118,"text":"A M Pandithage"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":691,"end":723,"text":"Kelani Valley Resorts, (Pvt) Ltd."}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":667,"end":723,"text":"fully-owned, subsidiary Kelani Valley Resorts, (Pvt) Ltd."}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":448,"end":484,"text":"Kalupahana, Power Company, (Pvt) Ltd."}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":406,"end":408,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":398,"end":421,"text":"Mabroc, Teas (Pvt) Ltd. "}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":353,"end":358,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":344,"end":346,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":156,"end":186,"text":"Hayleys Global, Beverages (Pvt)"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":122,"end":124,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":99,"end":135,"text":"Kelani, Valley Instant Tea, (Pvt) Ltd"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":70,"end":72,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":64,"end":72,"text":"green Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":40,"end":48,"text":"Glassaugh"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":24,"end":26,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":34,"text":"A.P. Certiﬁcation Black Tea factory"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548103005000,"last_updated_at":1548103005000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Appointed to the Board of Kelani Valley Plantations PLC in July 2009. Fellow of the Chartered Institute of Logistics and Transport (UK). Honorary Consul of United Mexican States (Mexico) to Sri Lanka. Committee Member of the Ceylon Chamber of Commerce. Council Member of the Employers’ Federation of Ceylon. Member of the Advisory Council of the Ceylon Association of Ships’Agents.","annotation":[{"label":["NORP"],"points":[{"start":225,"end":250,"text":"Ceylon Chamber of Commerce"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550245049000,"last_updated_at":1550245049000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Joined Kelani Valley Plantations PLC in 1995. Appointed to the Board in June 2009. Appointed as Chief Executive Ofﬁcer in April 2016. Fellow, Institute of Chartered Accountants of Sri Lanka and the Institute of Certiﬁed Management Accountants of Sri Lanka, and a member of the Institute of Certiﬁed Public Accountants of Sri, Lanka.","annotation":[{"label":["NORP"],"points":[{"start":277,"end":316,"text":"Institute of Certiﬁed Public Accountants"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":7,"end":35,"text":"Kelani Valley Plantations PLC"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550064690000,"last_updated_at":1550064690000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "02.  Roshan Rajadurai Managing Director/Executive Director, 04.  F Mohideen Independent Non-Executive Director, Managing Director of Kelani Valley Plantations PLC, Talawakelle, Tea Estates PLC from January 2013, a member of the Hayleys, Group Management Committee and Managing Director of Horana, Plantations PLC.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":289,"end":311,"text":"Horana, Plantations PLC"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":228,"end":241,"text":"Hayleys, Group"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":164,"end":191,"text":"Talawakelle, Tea Estates PLC"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":133,"end":161,"text":"Kelani Valley Plantations PLC"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":65,"end":75,"text":"F Mohideen "}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":5,"end":20,"text":"Roshan Rajadurai"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550212849000,"last_updated_at":1550212849000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Prior to rejoining, served as Director/CEO of Kahawatta Plantations PLC and held senior plantation management, positions in Kelani Valley Plantations PLC from 1993 to 2001. Holds a BSc. in Plantation Management and holds an MBA from Post Graduate Institute of Agriculture, Peradeniya.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":124,"end":152,"text":"Kelani Valley Plantations PLC"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":46,"end":70,"text":"Kahawatta Plantations PLC"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550239022000,"last_updated_at":1550239022000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Fellow Member of National Institute of Plantation Management (NIPM), Institute, of Management of Sri Lanka (IMSL) and Institute of Certiﬁed, Professional Managers (CPM). He was the Chairman of the Planters’ Association of Ceylon.","annotation":[{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":97,"end":105,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["NORP"],"points":[{"start":17,"end":66,"text":"National Institute of Plantation Management (NIPM)"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550091823000,"last_updated_at":1550091823000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Member of the Sri Lanka Tea Board, Rubber Research Board, Tea Council of Sri Lanka and Director, Tea Small Holdings Development Authority.","annotation":[{"label":["NORP"],"points":[{"start":97,"end":136,"text":"Tea Small Holdings Development Authority"}]},{"label":["NORP"],"points":[{"start":58,"end":81,"text":"Tea Council of Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["NORP"],"points":[{"start":35,"end":56,"text":"Rubber Research Board,"}]},{"label":["NORP"],"points":[{"start":14,"end":32,"text":"Sri Lanka Tea Board"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550067328000,"last_updated_at":1550067328000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Worked for the Hayleys Group between 1987 and 2002. Subsequently he held several senior management positions in large private sector entities in Sri Lanka and overseas. Has responsibility for the Strategic Business Development unit of the, Hayleys Group and the Fentons Group.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":262,"end":274,"text":"Fentons Group"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":240,"end":252,"text":"Hayleys Group"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":145,"end":153,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":15,"end":27,"text":"Hayleys Group"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550091245000,"last_updated_at":1550091271000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, 06.  L T Samarawickrama Non-Executive Director, 08.  C V Cabraal Independent Non-Executive Director, Director of Kelani Valley Plantations PLC since November 2009. An internationally-qualiﬁed hotelier having gained most of his, management experience in the UK, working for large international, hotel chains over a long period of time. The ﬁrst Sri Lankan manager to be appointed by the Beaufort International Chain, of Hotels to run the ﬁrst seaside boutique resort. A member of the Institute of Hospitality, UK (formerly HCIMA) and of the Royal, Society of Health, London. He has many years of experience in the trade, having specialised in hotel designs and development,, has been responsible for the careful planning and execution of, Amaya Resorts  Spas refurbishment and rehabilitation programs.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":792,"end":810,"text":"Amaya Resorts  Spas"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":563,"end":564,"text":"UK"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":398,"end":407,"text":"Sri Lankan"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":311,"end":312,"text":"UK"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":167,"end":195,"text":"Kelani Valley Plantations PLC"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":59,"end":76,"text":"L T Samarawickrama"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550242701000,"last_updated_at":1550242701000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "An Executive Director of Hayleys PLC and the Managing Director of, Amaya Leisure PLC, Hunas Falls, Sun Tan Beach Resorts, Luxury, Resorts Maldives, Hayleys Tours (Pvt) Ltd., a Director of Royal Ceramics Lanka PLC, Royal Porcelain (Private) Limited, Royal, Ceramics Distributors (Pvt) Ltd., Rocell Bathware Limited, Culture Club Resorts (Pvt) Ltd. and Deputy Chairman of The Fortress Resorts PLC.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":148,"end":171,"text":"Hayleys Tours (Pvt) Ltd."}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":67,"end":83,"text":"Amaya Leisure PLC"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":25,"end":35,"text":"Hayleys PLC"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550093190000,"last_updated_at":1550093190000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "07.  Dr. K I M Ranasoma Non-Executive Director, Director of Kelani Valley Plantations PLC since October 2011. Joined DPL in August 2010 as an Executive Director and took over, as Managing Director from April 2011. Appointed to the Hayleys Group Management Committee in January 2011 and to the Board, of Hayleys in April 2011. Former Country Chairman/Managing Director of Shell Gas Lanka Ltd. and Shell Terminal Lanka Ltd. Holds First Class Honours Degree in Engineering from the University, of Peradeniya, Sri Lanka, a Doctorate from Cambridge University,, UK and an MBA with Distinction from Wales University, UK. Appointed to the Board in January 2013. A Graduate (with Honours) in Mechanical Engineering (BSc.) with a focus in manufacturing and design from the Missouri University of Science, and Technology. He is currently working for CHEC Port City Colombo (Pvt) Ltd. in the Property Development Department. Worked at Brandix Lanka (Pvt) Ltd. as a Sustainability Engineer (2011-2014) in the Energy and Environment Department.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":924,"end":947,"text":"Brandix Lanka (Pvt) Ltd."}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":840,"end":872,"text":"CHEC Port City Colombo (Pvt) Ltd."}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":764,"end":782,"text":"Missouri University"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":611,"end":612,"text":"UK"}]},{"label":["NORP"],"points":[{"start":593,"end":608,"text":"Wales University"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":557,"end":558,"text":"UK"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":534,"end":553,"text":"Cambridge University"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":506,"end":514,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":494,"end":503,"text":"Peradeniya"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":479,"end":503,"text":"University, of Peradeniya"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":396,"end":420,"text":"Shell Terminal Lanka Ltd."}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":371,"end":390,"text":"Shell Gas Lanka Ltd."}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":303,"end":309,"text":"Hayleys"}]},{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":269,"end":280,"text":"January 2011"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":231,"end":243,"text":"Hayleys Group"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":231,"end":237,"text":"Hayleys"}]},{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":124,"end":134,"text":"August 2010"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":117,"end":119,"text":"DPL"}]},{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":96,"end":107,"text":"October 2011"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":60,"end":88,"text":"Kelani Valley Plantations PLC"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":5,"end":22,"text":"Dr. K I M Ranasoma"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548143434000,"last_updated_at":1548143434000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "The co-owner and co-founder of Royal Orchids (Pvt) Ltd. which owns and operates a ﬂoriculture farm. Serves on the Boards of Vallibel Power Erathna PLC and The, Fortress Resort and Spa PLC.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":160,"end":187,"text":"Fortress Resort and Spa PLC."}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":124,"end":150,"text":"Vallibel Power Erathna PLC "}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":31,"end":53,"text":"Royal Orchids (Pvt) Ltd"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548100680000,"last_updated_at":1548100680000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "09.  L N De S Wijeyeratne Independent Non-Executive Director, Appointed to the Board of Kelani Valley Plantations PLC in July, 2013. Fellow of the Institute of Chartered Accountants in Sri Lanka and counts over 35 years of experience in ﬁnance and, general management both in Sri Lanka and overseas. Former Group Finance Director of Richard Pieris PLC and also held senior, management positions at Aitken Spence & Company, Brooke, Bonds Ceylon and Zambia Consolidated Copper Mines Limited.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":398,"end":420,"text":"Aitken Spence & Company"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":333,"end":350,"text":"Richard Pieris PLC"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":276,"end":284,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":185,"end":193,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":88,"end":116,"text":"Kelani Valley Plantations PLC"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":5,"end":24,"text":"L N De S Wijeyeratne"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550212483000,"last_updated_at":1550212483000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "An Independent Director of several listed and unlisted companies. KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, Corporate Management Profile, BOARD OF DIRECTORS, Kelani Valley Plantations PLC, Tea and Rubber plantations, Incorporated in 1992 in Sri Lanka, Stated capital – Rs. 340 m Directors:, A M Pandithage - Chairman, Roshan Rajadurai - Managing Director, S Siriwardana - Chief Executive Ofﬁcer, F Mohideen, S C Ganegoda, L T Samarawickrama, Dr. K I M Ranasoma C V Cabraal, L N De S Wijeyeratne, DPL Plantations (Pvt) Ltd. Plantation Management, Managing Agent, Incorporated in 1992 in Sri Lanka, Stated capital – Rs. 350 m Directors:, A M Pandithage - Chairman, Roshan Rajadurai, S Siriwardana, S C Ganegoda, Dr. K I M Ranasoma Kalupahana Power Company (Pvt) Ltd. Generates hydro power, Incorporated in 2003 in Sri Lanka, Stated capital – Rs. 30 m, Group interest Mabroc Teas (Pvt) Ltd. Exports bulk and retail packed Tea, Incorporated in 1988 in Sri Lanka, Stated capital – Rs. 90 m, Group interest Directors:, S Siriwardana, Dr. K I M Ranasoma Roshan Rajadurai, M F M Ismail, L G Perera, Kelani Valley Instant Tea (Pvt) Ltd. Manufactures instant Tea, Incorporated in 2007 in Sri Lanka, Stated Capital - Rs. 30 m, Group Interest Directors:, A M Pandithage, N R Ranatunga, Dr. K I M Ranasoma Roshan Rajadurai, Directors:, A M Pandithage - Chairman, J A G Anandarajah, N R Ranatunga - Managing Director, R M Hanwella, Roshan Rajadurai, Dr. K I M Ranasoma M R Zaheed (Resigned w.","annotation":[{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1467,"end":1476,"text":"M R Zaheed"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1448,"end":1465,"text":"Dr. K I M Ranasoma"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1430,"end":1445,"text":"Roshan Rajadurai"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1416,"end":1427,"text":"R M Hanwella"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1381,"end":1393,"text":"N R Ranatunga"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1362,"end":1378,"text":"J A G Anandarajah"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1335,"end":1348,"text":"A M Pandithage"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1305,"end":1320,"text":"Roshan Rajadurai"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1286,"end":1303,"text":"Dr. K I M Ranasoma"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1271,"end":1283,"text":"N R Ranatunga"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1255,"end":1268,"text":"A M Pandithage"}]},{"label":["MONEY"],"points":[{"start":1218,"end":1225,"text":"Rs. 30 m"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":1190,"end":1198,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":1161,"end":1163,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":1153,"end":1163,"text":"instant Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":1125,"end":1127,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":1103,"end":1138,"text":"Kelani Valley Instant Tea (Pvt) Ltd."}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1091,"end":1100,"text":"L G Perera"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1077,"end":1088,"text":"M F M Ismail"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1059,"end":1074,"text":"Roshan Rajadurai"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1040,"end":1057,"text":"Dr. K I M Ranasoma"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":1025,"end":1037,"text":"S Siriwardana"}]},{"label":["MONEY"],"points":[{"start":988,"end":995,"text":"Rs. 90 m"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":960,"end":968,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":952,"end":955,"text":"1988"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":931,"end":933,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":884,"end":886,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":877,"end":897,"text":"Mabroc Teas (Pvt) Ltd"}]},{"label":["MONEY"],"points":[{"start":852,"end":859,"text":"Rs. 30 m"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":824,"end":832,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":816,"end":819,"text":"2003"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":787,"end":797,"text":"hydro power"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":741,"end":775,"text":"Kalupahana Power Company (Pvt) Ltd."}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":722,"end":739,"text":"Dr. K I M Ranasoma"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":708,"end":719,"text":"S C Ganegoda"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":693,"end":705,"text":"S Siriwardana"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":675,"end":690,"text":"Roshan Rajadurai"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":648,"end":661,"text":"A M Pandithage"}]},{"label":["MONEY"],"points":[{"start":626,"end":634,"text":"Rs. 350 m"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":598,"end":606,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":590,"end":593,"text":"1992"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":508,"end":532,"text":"DPL Plantations (Pvt) Ltd"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":486,"end":505,"text":"L N De S Wijeyeratne"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":473,"end":483,"text":"C V Cabraal"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":454,"end":471,"text":"Dr. K I M Ranasoma"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":434,"end":451,"text":"L T Samarawickrama"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":420,"end":431,"text":"S C Ganegoda"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":408,"end":417,"text":"F Mohideen"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":368,"end":380,"text":"S Siriwardana"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":330,"end":345,"text":"Roshan Rajadurai"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":303,"end":316,"text":"A M Pandithage"}]},{"label":["MONEY"],"points":[{"start":281,"end":290,"text":"Rs. 340 m "}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":253,"end":261,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":245,"end":248,"text":"1992"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":201,"end":226,"text":"Tea and Rubber plantations"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":201,"end":203,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":170,"end":198,"text":"Kelani Valley Plantations PLC"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548143252000,"last_updated_at":1548143252000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "e.f. 31-03-2018) R S Samarasinghe (Appointed w.","annotation":[{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":17,"end":32,"text":"R S Samarasinghe"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550243288000,"last_updated_at":1550243288000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "e.f. S C Ganegoda (Appointed w.","annotation":[{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":5,"end":16,"text":"S C Ganegoda"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548100417000,"last_updated_at":1548100417000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "The Rubber industry, which has seen a downturn in fortunes for, the past two years, is an example of the, severity of the problem.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":4,"end":9,"text":"Rubber"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550092797000,"last_updated_at":1550092797000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "In contrast, the Tea industry appears to, be a beacon of hope for the country’s, agriculture sector, posting a greatly, improved performance in 2017. Despite negative headwinds caused by the weather, and other serious challenges facing, the industry, including the Glyphosate, weedicide ban, Sri Lanka’s Tea output, increased by 5.17% year-on-year. The global Tea shortage witnessed due to, declining production volumes in Kenya, and North India was a boon for local, industry, which beneﬁtted from strong, demand and higher prices throughout the, year.","annotation":[{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":434,"end":444,"text":"North India"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":423,"end":427,"text":"Kenya"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":360,"end":362,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":304,"end":306,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":292,"end":300,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":265,"end":313,"text":"Glyphosate, weedicide ban, Sri Lanka’s Tea output"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":17,"end":28,"text":"Tea industry"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":17,"end":19,"text":"Tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548096121000,"last_updated_at":1548096121000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Currently our main strategic thrust is, centered on migrating to a more agile, business framework that would enable, the Company to sustainably scale up, operations in the long-term and are now, focusing our business transformation, efforts to enter a new age of efﬁciency,, sustainability and innovation throughout, both our Tea and Rubber value chains.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":334,"end":339,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":326,"end":328,"text":"Tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550061177000,"last_updated_at":1550061177000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "The Company’s strategic decision, to expedite the Crop Diversiﬁcation, model, has led to a signiﬁcant increase, in Cinnamon cultivation of almost 100, hectares as at 31 March 2018. The shortage of workers remains a, critical challenge that we face in both, Tea and Rubber plantations, especially, KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, Chairman’s Message Contd. in recent times where worker migration, has increased to urban cities in the, country and overseas seeking better, prospects.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":265,"end":270,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":257,"end":259,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":166,"end":178,"text":"31 March 2018"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550213184000,"last_updated_at":1550213184000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Spearheading this effort is the revenue-, sharing model rolled out as a pilot project, in mid-2017 in predominant Tea cultivated, estates.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":114,"end":116,"text":"Tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550063305000,"last_updated_at":1550063305000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "PERFORMANCE, KVPL turnover for the year in review, increased by 28% over the corresponding, year mainly due to the increased Tea, production and a high prices for its end, product. The net proﬁt after tax increased to Rs. 326 m for the ﬁnancial year under review.","annotation":[{"label":["MONEY"],"points":[{"start":218,"end":226,"text":"Rs. 326 m"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":125,"end":127,"text":"Tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550242832000,"last_updated_at":1550242832000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "The Group’s turnover for the year under, review increased by 26% to Rs. 8.6 b over the previous year and Mabroc Teas our, marketing subsidiary, with a turnover of, Rs. 4.5 b, being the main contributor. KVPL Group recorded Rs. 160 m net proﬁt after tax over the ﬁnancial year, under consideration.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":105,"end":115,"text":"Mabroc Teas"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550067213000,"last_updated_at":1550067213000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Mabroc Teas (Pvt) Ltd., recorded yet another good year with the highest export volume on record in, its history.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":21,"text":"Mabroc Teas (Pvt) Ltd."}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550155318000,"last_updated_at":1550155318000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "With favorable wide spread rain fall received in and around the hydro, catchment area of Kalupahana Power, Company (Pvt) Ltd., the power generation was higher over the corresponding year,, which also contributed positively towards, the Groups proﬁtability.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":89,"end":124,"text":"Kalupahana Power, Company (Pvt) Ltd."}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550239465000,"last_updated_at":1550239465000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Hayleys Global Beverages (Pvt) Ltd., the state of the art Tea extract plant in Hatton is, awaiting approval of our samples with major, overseas tea extract buyers to executing, commercial orders. We are optimistic that the company would turn around in the, near future, as several large B2B players, in the tea extract industry have shown, interest. Kelani Valley Resorts (Pvt) Ltd., the newest venture of the Group, with its “The, Oliphant Boutique Bungalow”, commenced, operations in December 2017 which is, managed by Amaya Leisure PLC has shown, potential in its short spell since operation, receiving good reviews from the travelers. Based on your Company’s performance for, the ﬁnancial year concluded, the Directors, have proposed a ﬁnal dividend of Rs. 1.00 per share.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":521,"end":537,"text":"Amaya Leisure PLC"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":427,"end":457,"text":"The, Oliphant Boutique Bungalow"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":350,"end":381,"text":"Kelani Valley Resorts (Pvt) Ltd."}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":34,"text":"Hayleys Global Beverages (Pvt) Ltd."}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550067939000,"last_updated_at":1550067939000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "FUTURE PLANS, With the positive outlook for Sri Lanka’s, economy, I expect the coming year would, bring strong growth possibilities for KVPL’s, Tea and Rubber businesses.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":152,"end":157,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":144,"end":146,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":44,"end":52,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550064576000,"last_updated_at":1550064576000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "On behalf of the Board, I reiterate the commitment to keep, on enhancing the value delivered to all, stakeholders in the years ahead. A M Pandithage, Chairman, 09 May 2018, KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, Managing Director’s Message, GRI 102-14, Keeping our,   eyes on the prize, We’ve made great strides as a company, that’s keen to shake up the industry, Taking a holistic approach, we, deployed multiple strategies to, focus on enhancing not only our, financial performance, but, also crucially looking at how we, can enrich the lives of our people.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":227,"end":255,"text":"KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":173,"end":201,"text":"KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC"}]},{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":160,"end":170,"text":"09 May 2018"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":134,"end":147,"text":"A M Pandithage"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550242985000,"last_updated_at":1550242985000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Throughout the year we looked to consolidate our core competencies and, push for a more sustainable operating, model that would not only to spearhead, growth of the core businesses but also, enable us to work from the ground-up to, help the country’s Tea and Rubber sectors, to thrive and grow well into the future.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":259,"end":264,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":251,"end":272,"text":"Tea and Rubber sectors"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":251,"end":253,"text":"Tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548144563000,"last_updated_at":1548144563000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, KVPL TEA, KVPL’s Tea operations performed, exceedingly well in the year under review,, with revenues reporting a 27% increase, from Rs. 6,164 m in the previous year to Rs.7, 540 m for 2017/18. Higher turnover was the result of a 14% increase in the, Tea crop together with signiﬁcantly higher, prices at the Colombo Tea auction.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":370,"end":372,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":362,"end":380,"text":"Colombo Tea auction"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":304,"end":306,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":71,"end":73,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":54,"end":61,"text":"KVPL TEA"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":28,"text":"KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550211818000,"last_updated_at":1550211818000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "At this point it is worth mentioning that while the, national average high-grown Tea crop for, 2017 was unchanged from 2016, KVPL, reported a commendable 14% increase in, the high grown Tea crop, which I believe is, largely thanks to the proper application of, the revenue-share model.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":186,"end":193,"text":"Tea crop"}]},{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":119,"end":122,"text":"2016"}]},{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":95,"end":99,"text":"2017 "}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":81,"end":88,"text":"Tea crop"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548142447000,"last_updated_at":1548142447000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "In similar vein we continued to invest on upkeep of our, factory infrastructure and equipment in, keeping to our quality and safety standards, in compliance with our certiﬁcation. We continued our corporate standing, of being a preferred tea producer by, committing to sustain the certiﬁcation, standards of all our 12 tea processing, centres as ISO 22000:2005 food safety, management system, and conform to UTZ,, Rainforest Alliance and the Ethical Tea, Partnership. COMMUNITY INVESTMENT, I am also happy to report that KVPL, made good progress on its community, developments efforts operationalized, through our ﬂagship community initiative, “A Home for every Plantation worker”, programme, which also conﬁrms KVPL’s, alignment to the 10 principles outlined in, the UN Global Compact. The programme continues to receive international acclaim, and received a considerable boost in the, year under review, following the interest, shown by the Save the Children Fund, to integrate the concept of Mother-and-, child-friendly Tea estates into the main, programme framework. As part of the ﬁrst phase of the initiative, the Child Policy was, rolled out across all estates, with KVPL, making history as the ﬁrst-ever plantation, company anywhere in the world to adopt, the policy.","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":346,"end":371,"text":"ISO 22000:2005 food safety"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":319,"end":321,"text":"tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":238,"end":240,"text":"tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550064219000,"last_updated_at":1550064219000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "It is encouraging to note that the success of, these initiatives has enabled KVPL to secure, assistance from other global organizations, to expedite our community development, agenda. Notable contributions for the year KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, include, the additional commitment by the, “Save the Children fund” under the UNGC -, CEO water mandate, to contribute towards, improving water and sanitation levels as, well as the upliftment of child development, centers at estates in the Hatton region. In yet another milestone achievement,, KVPL was able to secure the commitment, of the World Bank to develop necessary, infrastructure to provide puriﬁed drinking, water to 177 families at the Glassaugh, estate and another 540 families at the, Edinburgh estate. The project also included the construction of essential sanitation, facilities at both Edinburgh and Glassaugh, estates.","annotation":[{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":891,"end":908,"text":"Glassaugh, estates"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":891,"end":899,"text":"Glassaugh"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":877,"end":885,"text":"Edinburgh"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":772,"end":787,"text":"Edinburgh estate"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":772,"end":780,"text":"Edinburgh"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":721,"end":729,"text":"Glassaugh"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":514,"end":519,"text":"Hatton"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550090763000,"last_updated_at":1550090763000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "KVPL RUBBER, The Rubber segment too performed, reasonably well in the year under review,, despite some notable challenges. The sector came under stress as high prices, for Centrifuge Latex in the 3rd and 4th, quarters saw local buyers opting to import, their requirements at a lower cost.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":172,"end":187,"text":"Centrifuge Latex"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":10,"text":"KVPL RUBBER"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548095850000,"last_updated_at":1548095850000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "The scenario forced KVPL to shift towards the, manufacture of Crepe Rubber in order, to utilize latex stocks, which meant the, optimum product mix could not be achieved,, in turn bringing pressure on margins.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":62,"end":73,"text":"Crepe Rubber"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550238695000,"last_updated_at":1550238695000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Nonetheless, the segment’s revenue was, up by 13% to Rs. 1,043 m aided by higher export volumes of made Rubber and, increased prices at the Colombo Auctions. Notably, Rubber prices/kg (NSA) of all, grades shot up by 22% to Rs. 334/- per made Rubber kg from Rs. 274/-. I believe our performance for the, year under review puts Kelani, Valley Plantations PLC on track, towards its next big growth phase.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":326,"end":356,"text":"Kelani, Valley Plantations PLC "}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":242,"end":247,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":167,"end":172,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":104,"end":109,"text":"Rubber"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550092968000,"last_updated_at":1550092968000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "KVPL CINNAMON, We increased our investment in Cinnamon, cultivation with a total of 43.52 hectares of Cinnamon planted in the year under review.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":102,"end":109,"text":"Cinnamon"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":46,"end":53,"text":"Cinnamon"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":5,"end":12,"text":"CINNAMON"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":12,"text":"KVPL CINNAMON"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550238154000,"last_updated_at":1550238154000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "The cultivation of Cinnamon is more a, long-term strategy targeting larger extents, and adding value to its end products, the, results of which would add to our revenues, in the years to come. PERFORMANCE OF SUBSIDIARIES, Mabroc Teas (Pvt) Ltd., performed exceedingly well. The Company reported higher Turnover over the previous year, contributed by a larger volume of tea being, exported.","annotation":null,"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550067156000,"last_updated_at":1550067156000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "A signiﬁcant growth in exports to China has been observed while PBT too, KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, Managing Director’s Message Contd. increased for the period 2017/18. Financial performance appear in page 22 of this report, The performance of Kalupahana Power, Company (Pvt) Ltd. (KPC), also showed a strong improvement for the year under, review. The Company increased its contribution to the national grid by 55%, enabling a 47% increase in turnover to Rs. Rs. 32 m, from Rs. 21 m in the previous year.","annotation":[{"label":["MONEY"],"points":[{"start":502,"end":509,"text":"Rs. 21 m"}]},{"label":["MONEY"],"points":[{"start":487,"end":494,"text":"Rs. 32 m"}]},{"label":["PERCENT"],"points":[{"start":455,"end":457,"text":"47%"}]},{"label":["PERCENT"],"points":[{"start":438,"end":441,"text":" 55%"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":270,"end":306,"text":" Kalupahana Power, Company (Pvt) Ltd."}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":34,"end":38,"text":"China"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550243207000,"last_updated_at":1550243207000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "However KPC’s  the bottom line took a hit of Rs. 2 m, as a result of the backdated tariff adjustment imposed by the Ceylon, Electricity Board in the latter part of the year.","annotation":[{"label":["NORP"],"points":[{"start":116,"end":140,"text":"Ceylon, Electricity Board"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550065124000,"last_updated_at":1550065124000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Kelani Valley Resorts (Pvt) Ltd. (KVR) reported revenue of Rs. 6 m and a gross proﬁt of Rs. 4.7 m for the three months ending 31 March 2018. KVR owns the bungalow at “Oliphant Estate” situated in, Nuwara Eliya, which was refurbished and, launched to the market in October 2017, as a luxury boutique hotel offering a truly, colonial experience.","annotation":[{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":197,"end":208,"text":"Nuwara Eliya"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":167,"end":181,"text":"Oliphant Estate"}]},{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":126,"end":138,"text":"31 March 2018"}]},{"label":["MONEY"],"points":[{"start":88,"end":96,"text":"Rs. 4.7 m"}]},{"label":["MONEY"],"points":[{"start":59,"end":65,"text":"Rs. 6 m"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":31,"text":"Kelani Valley Resorts (Pvt) Ltd."}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550244876000,"last_updated_at":1550244876000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Hayley’s Global Beverages (Pvt) Ltd. (HGBL), the state of the art Tea Extract, Plant in Hatton has continued its, product sampling and testing with many, buyers showing interest in these new, developments. While no conﬁrmed outcomes have yet materialised, we remain, conﬁdent that the company would fare well, in due course. In the meantime, HGBL’s loss amounting to Rs. 213 m for the year under review was absorbed by KVPL.","annotation":[{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":88,"end":93,"text":"Hatton"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":66,"end":68,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":35,"text":"Hayley’s Global Beverages (Pvt) Ltd."}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550239414000,"last_updated_at":1550239414000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "FUTURE OUTLOOK, I believe our performance for the year, under review puts Kelani Valley Plantations, PLC on track towards its next big growth, phase.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":74,"end":103,"text":"Kelani Valley Plantations, PLC"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548053816000,"last_updated_at":1548053816000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "We remain optimistic about the future and will look to further consolidate, our position and improve yields in both Tea, and Rubber segments.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":125,"end":130,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":116,"end":118,"text":"Tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550244656000,"last_updated_at":1550244656000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "In the Rubber segment, we expect, replanting to remain a high a priority.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":7,"end":12,"text":"Rubber"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550061451000,"last_updated_at":1550061451000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Further we will also look to expedite our, crop diversiﬁcation strategies by exploring, the possibility of investing in coconut.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":120,"end":126,"text":"coconut"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548100365000,"last_updated_at":1548100365000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Roshan Rajadurai, Managing Director, Kelani Valley Plantations PLC, KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, the change, you want to see, in theworld, - MAHATMA GANDHI -, Our cinnamon is truly a Sri Lankan effort,, with new ventures sure to add spice, to our already-diverse portfolio. KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, Stakeholder Engagement, Plantations can no longer choose if they want to engage with stakeholders or not. The only decision we need to take is when and how successfully engage.","annotation":[{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":208,"end":217,"text":"Sri Lankan"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":188,"end":195,"text":"cinnamon"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":37,"end":65,"text":"Kelani Valley Plantations PLC"}]},{"label":["PERSON"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":15,"text":"Roshan Rajadurai"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550212582000,"last_updated_at":1550212582000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "(cid:138)(cid:3) Labour intensive, operation, (cid:138)(cid:3) Maintaining good, employee relations, is critical to ensure, sustainability, (cid:138)(cid:3) Commitment to uplift, the living standards, of estate-worker, communities, (cid:138)(cid:3) Governance, in compliance, with statutes and, regulations, (cid:138)(cid:3) Complies with, regulations and new, standards set for the, industry, (cid:138)(cid:3) To ensure greater, sustainability, the, Company conducts, its operations in a, responsible manner, (cid:138)(cid:3) KVPL operates on, 25 Tea and Rubber, estates comprising, green latex and leaf, operations in low,, medium and high, grown elevations, (cid:138)(cid:3) The Company brings, economic prosperity, to its workforce of, over 9,000 people, and a dependent, population of over, 55,000 who are part, of the larger resident, community at KVPL’s, estates.","annotation":[{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":854,"end":868,"text":"KVPL’s, estates"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":584,"end":594,"text":"green latex"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":556,"end":561,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":548,"end":550,"text":"Tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548144737000,"last_updated_at":1548144737000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Method of measure, and monitor, (cid:138)(cid:3) Community investments, (cid:138)(cid:3) Number of community, programs/initiatives rolled, Total water consumption, Total energy consumption, (cid:138)(cid:3), (cid:138)(cid:3), (cid:138)(cid:3) GHG emissions, (cid:138)(cid:3) Waste generated by weight/, volume, KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, Materiality Assessment Contd. (cid:138)(cid:3) Water, (cid:138)(cid:3) Grievance mechanisms for impacts, on society, (cid:138)(cid:3) Emissions, (cid:138)(cid:3) Product and services, (cid:138)(cid:3) Product and service labelling, (cid:138)(cid:3) Procurement practices, (cid:138)(cid:3) Materials, (cid:138)(cid:3) Compliance, (cid:138)(cid:3) Transport, (cid:138)(cid:3) Labour/management relations, (cid:138)(cid:3) Diversity and equal opportunity, (cid:138)(cid:3) Equal remuneration for women and, Indirect economic impacts, (cid:138)(cid:3), (cid:138)(cid:3) Environmental grievance mechanisms, (cid:138)(cid:3) Supplier assessment for labour, practices, (cid:138)(cid:3) Supplier human rights assessment, (cid:138)(cid:3) Human rights grievance mechanisms, (cid:138)(cid:3) Anti-competitive behaviour, (cid:138)(cid:3) Customer privacy, (cid:138)(cid:3) Economic performance, (cid:138)(cid:3) Market presence, (cid:138)(cid:3) Legal, environment and society, compliance, (cid:138)(cid:3) Forced or compulsory labour, (cid:138)(cid:3) Biodiversity, (cid:138)(cid:3) Energy, (cid:138)(cid:3) Efﬂuent and waste, (cid:138)(cid:3) Child labour, (cid:138)(cid:3) Freedom of association and collective, bargaining, Investments, (cid:138)(cid:3), (cid:138)(cid:3) Non-discrimination, (cid:138)(cid:3) Security practices, (cid:138)(cid:3) Training and education, (cid:138)(cid:3) Employment, (cid:138)(cid:3) Occupational Health and Safety, (cid:138)(cid:3) Local communities, (cid:138)(cid:3) Anti-corruption, (cid:138)(cid:3) Supplier assessment for impacts on, society, Indigenous rights, (cid:138)(cid:3), (cid:138)(cid:3) Public policy, (cid:138)(cid:3) Supplier environmental assessment, (cid:138)(cid:3) Labour practices grievance, mechanisms, Medium, High, Signiﬁcance to KVPL, KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, VALUE CHAIN, Good, Agriculture, Practices, Infrastructure, Development, Human Resource, Management, Tea plantation, Supplier/small holder, Company processing, Tea trading/auction sale, End user, Innovation and, Technological Development, Training and, Awareness, Company, Strategies and, Polices, KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, GRI 112-11, Creating Value for our Stakeholders, Vision, Capital, “Kelani Valley Plantations –, products of excellence”, Financial Capital, (cid:138)(cid:3) Strategic planning, (cid:138)(cid:3) Financial management, (cid:138)(cid:3) Risk management, (cid:138)(cid:3) Corporate governance, (cid:138)(cid:3), Investment, Natural Capital, (cid:138)(cid:3) Environment stewardship, (cid:138)(cid:3) Biodiversity and ecosystem, (cid:138)(cid:3) Sustainable resources, (cid:138)(cid:3) Environmental protection, (water, soil, energy), Human Capital, (cid:138)(cid:3) Dynamic HR framework, (cid:138)(cid:3) Commitment to UNGC, principles, (cid:138)(cid:3) HR strategic plan, (cid:138)(cid:3) Succession planning, Social & Relationship, Capital, (cid:138)(cid:3) Community development, (cid:138)(cid:3) Capacity building, (cid:138)(cid:3) Stakeholder relationship, Improving quality of life, (cid:138)(cid:3), Manufactured Capital, (cid:138)(cid:3) RA, FSC, ISO 22000 Certiﬁed, processing centres, (cid:138)(cid:3) Crop diversiﬁcation, (cid:138)(cid:3) Hydropower plants, (cid:138)(cid:3) Product for speciﬁc markets, Intellectual Capital, (cid:138)(cid:3) Product & market research, (cid:138)(cid:3), (cid:138)(cid:3) Customer engagement, (cid:138)(cid:3) Diversiﬁed business, Innovation and development, Strategy, Process, Customer, Engagement, B u s iness Domain, Hydro power/, Solar power, generation, Marketing, Business, Segments, Agro, Tourism, Tea and Rubber, estates, Quality, Assurance, Input, Plantation, Management, Support, Services, To optimise plantation productivity and ensure highest quality by, harnessing and developing employees whilst improving the quality of, life of the community and securing an acceptable return on investment. Sustainability, Practices, Output, Manufacturing, KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, Mission, Value, Financial Capital, (cid:138)(cid:3) EBITDA as % sales 7.2% (cid:138)(cid:3) ROCE 7.21% Capital expenditure Rs. 473 m (cid:138)(cid:3) ROA 2.06% Natural Capital, (cid:138)(cid:3), International accreditation & certiﬁcation -RA, FSC,, ETP, ISO 22000, GMP, (cid:138)(cid:3) Rs. 21.2 m spent for solar  power project (cid:138)(cid:3) Merit Award for Sustainable Forest Management, (cid:138)(cid:3) Rs. 104 m invested for efﬂuent treatment Human Capital, (cid:138)(cid:3) 9,568 head counts were trained, (cid:138)(cid:3) Developed HR team under human development in, each estate, (cid:138)(cid:3) Strengthening of organisational culture and values, (cid:138)(cid:3) Gold award at SLITAD People Development Awards, Social & Relationship Capital, (cid:138)(cid:3) Stakeholder satisfaction and trust, (cid:138)(cid:3) Health and safety of estate population, (cid:138)(cid:3) Community development, (cid:138)(cid:3) CSR through “Home for Every Plantation Worker” & Key, Value Drivers, (cid:138)(cid:3) Gold award for Excellence in CSR at National Business, Excellence Awards, Manufactured Capital, (cid:138)(cid:3), ISO 22000 Certiﬁed 11 black Tea factories and one, green Tea factory produced 5.1 m Kg Tea (cid:138)(cid:3) RA-FSC Certiﬁed Rubber factories Produced 2.9 m Kg Intellectual Capital, (cid:138)(cid:3) Boutique resort at Oliphant Bungalow, (cid:138)(cid:3) Direct market initiative to China, (cid:138)(cid:3), (cid:138)(cid:3) Diversiﬁcation into non-care crops on plantations, (cid:138)(cid:3), Introduction of fruit ﬂavoured Tea by Mabroc, Introduced new Tea packs, KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, Creating Value for our Stakeholders Contd. GRI 416-01,02, PRODUCT RESPONSIBILITY AND CUSTOMER HEALTH AND SAFETY, All products and processes are fully compliant with ISO 22000:2005 and HACCP, certiﬁcation issued by the Sri Lanka Accreditation Board.","annotation":[{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":5992,"end":6020,"text":"KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":5958,"end":5963,"text":"Mabroc"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":5936,"end":5953,"text":"fruit ﬂavoured Tea"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":5745,"end":5761,"text":"Oliphant Bungalow"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":5726,"end":5761,"text":"Boutique resort at Oliphant Bungalow"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":5652,"end":5657,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":5528,"end":5545,"text":"ISO 22000 Certiﬁed"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":4351,"end":4379,"text":"KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":4007,"end":4012,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":3914,"end":3924,"text":"Hydro power"}]},{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":3505,"end":3522,"text":"ISO 22000 Certiﬁed"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":2501,"end":2529,"text":"KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":2150,"end":2178,"text":"KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC"}]},{"label":["ORG"],"points":[{"start":311,"end":339,"text":"KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550062040000,"last_updated_at":1550062040000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Tea quality is tested annually for heavy metals, microbiological criteria and agro-chemical residues as, per the requirements of ISO 3720 standard.","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":129,"end":145,"text":"ISO 3720 standard"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":2,"text":"Tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550064166000,"last_updated_at":1550064166000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "In the case of Rubber, RA-FSC-COC certiﬁed standards are strictly maintained.","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":23,"end":51,"text":"RA-FSC-COC certiﬁed standards"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":15,"end":20,"text":"Rubber"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548053803000,"last_updated_at":1548053803000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "UTZ and RA standards further strengthen our alignment with international food safety, and quality management systems.","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":19,"text":"UTZ and RA standards"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548231743000,"last_updated_at":1548231743000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Further there were no complaints received on breach of customer privacy. KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, Creating Value for our Stakeholders Contd. GRI 102-09, SUPPLY CHAIN, Supply Chain, Agro-chemicals/, fertiliser, suppliers, Internal, transportation, Packing material, suppliers, Raw materials, (green leaf & ﬁeld latex), Cultivated lands, KVPL Head Ofﬁce, Manufacturing, facilities, Certification, bodies, Workers, Black Tea, Green Tea, Centrifuged, latex, Crepe &, sole crepe, Auction, Private sale, Customers, Fuel & electricity, suppliers, Machines & spare, parts suppliers, External, transportation, Bought leaf/ bought, latex suppliers, KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, Sector Reviews, GRI 102-15, EXTERNAL ENVIRONMENT, Global Economy, Source: Global Economic Prospects (January 2018), The global economy appears to have reached a turning point in 2017. Marking the end of the two year slump in economic activity, the global economy experienced, what is believed to be a cyclical recovery in 2017, reﬂecting a rebound in investment,, manufacturing activity, and trade. This improvement comes against the backdrop of benign global ﬁnancing conditions, generally accommodative policies, rising conﬁdence,, and ﬁrming commodity prices. According to data released by the Global Economic KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, Sector Reviews Contd. Prospects (January 2018) Report,, global GDP growth is estimated to have, picked up from 2.4% in 2016 to 3% in 2017, indicating it is on a clear path to, recovery.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":483,"end":501,"text":"Crepe &, sole crepe"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":463,"end":480,"text":"Centrifuged, latex"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":452,"end":460,"text":"Green Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":441,"end":449,"text":"Black Tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550244950000,"last_updated_at":1550244950000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "A further analysis reveals that advanced economies are estimated to, have rebounded strongly, driven by a, pickup in capital spending, a turnaround, in inventories, and strengthening external, demand. Notably, while growth appears to have accelerated in all major economies, in 2017, the improvement was markedly, stronger than expected in the Euro area.","annotation":[{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":344,"end":352,"text":"Euro area"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548100875000,"last_updated_at":1548100875000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Sri Lankan Economy, Source: CBSL, As per ofﬁcial data released by the, Department of Census and Statistics, (DCS), Sri Lanka’s real GDP growth, decelerated further during 2017 to 3.1 per cent, from the growth of 4.5 per cent recorded in 2016. Agriculture related activities recorded a contraction of 0.8 per cent against the backdrop of adverse, weather conditions that continued from, 2016, while a slowdown in economic, activity in both the services and industrial, sectors was observed. Industry related activities, accounting for, 26.8 per cent of real GDP, grew by 3.9 per cent in 2017. The growth in industrial activities was primarily supported by, manufacturing activities, construction, activities, and mining and quarrying.","annotation":[{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":586,"end":589,"text":"2017"}]},{"label":["CARDINAL"],"points":[{"start":570,"end":572,"text":"3.9"}]},{"label":["CARDINAL"],"points":[{"start":535,"end":538,"text":"26.8"}]},{"label":["CARDINAL"],"points":[{"start":300,"end":302,"text":"0.8"}]},{"label":["CARDINAL"],"points":[{"start":212,"end":214,"text":"4.5"}]},{"label":["CARDINAL"],"points":[{"start":179,"end":181,"text":"3.1"}]},{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":171,"end":174,"text":"2017"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":115,"end":123,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":9,"text":"Sri Lankan"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":8,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548128659000,"last_updated_at":1548128659000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Inﬂation, Headline inﬂation, measured using the, National Consumer Price Index as well, as the Colombo Consumer Price Index, remained high during the ﬁrst quarter of, 2017, impacted by supply side disruptions, resulting from adverse weather conditions as, well as the effect of upward tax revisions.","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":95,"end":122,"text":"Colombo Consumer Price Index"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550155571000,"last_updated_at":1550155571000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Global Tea Exports, Of the major Tea producing and exporting countries, India led the way with an 8.2% increase in export volumes. Bangladesh also reported an increase in its Tea exports in 2017, despite the low production levels reported for the year, while Kenyan Tea exports, declined 13.44%. Sri Lanka’s export volumes remained on par with the previous year. World Crop Statistics in (m/Kgs), Month - Dec, Todate, Difference, Sri Lanka, Bangaladesh, North India, South India, Kenya, Malawi, (Source - Forbes & Walker Research), SRI LANKA’S TEA INDUSTRY, Production Output, Sri Lanka’s Tea output increased by 5% to 307 m kilograms in 2017 from 292 m kilograms, in 2016. Of this, the low grown elevation Teas reported the strongest year-on-year increase of 7%, while medium-grown Teas registered a marginal 2% increase compared to the, previous year and high-grown output stayed on par with the previous year.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":783,"end":785,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":707,"end":709,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PERCENT"],"points":[{"start":613,"end":614,"text":"5%"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":589,"end":591,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":577,"end":585,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":544,"end":546,"text":"TEA"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":532,"end":540,"text":"SRI LANKA"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":487,"end":492,"text":"Malawi"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":480,"end":484,"text":"Kenya"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":473,"end":477,"text":"India"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":460,"end":464,"text":"India"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":441,"end":451,"text":"Bangaladesh"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":430,"end":438,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":296,"end":304,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":266,"end":268,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":259,"end":264,"text":"Kenyan"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":259,"end":263,"text":"Kenya"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":175,"end":177,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":131,"end":140,"text":"Bangladesh"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":72,"end":76,"text":"India"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":33,"end":35,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":7,"end":9,"text":"Tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550239377000,"last_updated_at":1550239377000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Meanwhile, a category-wise segmentation indicated a moderate 4% growth in orthodox Tea volumes, while CTC and Green Tea volumes were signiﬁcantly higher by 16.6% and 13% respectively compared to the previous year.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":116,"end":118,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":83,"end":85,"text":"Tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548101739000,"last_updated_at":1548101739000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Challenges faced by Sri Lanka’s Tea Industry, Despite its strong performance, Sri Lanka’s Tea industry was plagued by a number of constraints, in 2017. Among the most signiﬁcant challenges facing the local industry was the continuing unfavourable weather, undoubtedly the impact of climate change.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":90,"end":92,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":78,"end":86,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":32,"end":43,"text":"Tea Industry"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":32,"end":34,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":20,"end":28,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550212142000,"last_updated_at":1550212142000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Consequently, the deprecation of the Sri Lankan rupee, was contained to a marginal 2.2% against the US dollar for the nine months, ending September 2017. However, the Real Effective Exchange Rate (REER), indice, which also takes into account the, inﬂation differential amongst countries, in the currency basket, depreciated, considerably during the period under, review, but remained above the 100, threshold, suggesting the need for, further depreciation to reach the level of, competitiveness that prevailed in 2010. GLOBAL TEA INDUSTRY UPDATE, Global Tea Output, By far the strongest increase in output, among major Tea producing countries was, reported by Sri Lanka, where Tea output, grew by 14.5 m kilograms. Production in India was favourable with an 11.47 m kilogram growth for 2017. Other major Tea producing nations such as Kenya, Uganda, and Bangladesh reported a lower output in, 2017 compared to the previous calendar, year.","annotation":[{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":853,"end":862,"text":"Bangladesh"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":841,"end":846,"text":"Uganda"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":834,"end":838,"text":"Kenya"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":804,"end":806,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":729,"end":733,"text":"India"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":677,"end":679,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":660,"end":668,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":619,"end":621,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":554,"end":556,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":526,"end":528,"text":"TEA"}]},{"label":["PERCENT"],"points":[{"start":83,"end":86,"text":"2.2%"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":37,"end":45,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550243911000,"last_updated_at":1550243911000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "The EU and Japan have placed clear guidelines, on maximum allowable residue levels of, MCPA in made Tea, again putting the, country’s Tea industry at risk of losing out on, the opportunity to supply to these markets.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":134,"end":136,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":100,"end":102,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":11,"end":15,"text":"Japan"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":4,"end":5,"text":"EU"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550212205000,"last_updated_at":1550212205000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Export Volumes and Earnings, Sri Lanka exported a total of 0.21 m kilograms more Tea in 2017 than in 2016. Overall Turkey emerged as the leading buyer of Ceylon Tea, followed by Iraq and Russia, and Iran, closing up the top four.","annotation":[{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":199,"end":202,"text":"Iran"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":187,"end":192,"text":"Russia"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":178,"end":181,"text":"Iraq"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":161,"end":163,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":154,"end":163,"text":"Ceylon Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":115,"end":120,"text":"Turkey"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":81,"end":83,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":29,"end":37,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550063533000,"last_updated_at":1550063533000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Although Russia’s refusal to accept Tea imports upon the discovery of a ‘khapra beetle’ in a single consignment of Tea caused some temporary uncertainty in, mid-December 2017, quick action by local authorities to initiate urgent talks with Russian, Agricultural Safety representatives led to a speedy resolution with Tea exports to Russia, resuming shortly after under more stringent conditions.","annotation":[{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":332,"end":337,"text":"Russia"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":317,"end":319,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":240,"end":245,"text":"Russia"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":115,"end":117,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":36,"end":38,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":9,"end":14,"text":"Russia"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550240085000,"last_updated_at":1550240095000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "China and Taiwan have made noteworthy purchases of Tea from Colomb,o adding a greater demand. Meanwhile with the drop in Kenya’s Tea production levels causing a shortage in global CTC Teas, Sri Lanka, moved in to swiftly capitalise on the opportunity to supply to key buyers of CTC Teas. Kgs (‘000), Sri Lanka Tea Exports - 2010 to 2017, Value Rs. m QTY (Kgs), Value (Rs.) Year, (Source - Sri Lanka Customs), Sri Lanka Tea Exports-2010 to 2017, QTY(Kgs), Value(Rs.) KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, Sri Lanka earned a record USD 1,530.59 m from Tea exports in 2017, thanks to, consistently high prices at the Colombo, Tea Auctions.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":639,"end":641,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":630,"end":650,"text":"Colombo, Tea Auctions"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":630,"end":636,"text":"Colombo"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":566,"end":568,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["MONEY"],"points":[{"start":546,"end":559,"text":"USD 1,530.59 m"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":520,"end":528,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":419,"end":421,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":409,"end":417,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":389,"end":397,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":310,"end":312,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":300,"end":308,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":282,"end":284,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":190,"end":198,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":184,"end":186,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":129,"end":131,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":121,"end":125,"text":"Kenya"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":60,"end":67,"text":"Colomb,o"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":51,"end":53,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":10,"end":15,"text":"Taiwan"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":4,"text":"China"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548101525000,"last_updated_at":1548101541000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Tea Auction Prices, The short supply of CTC black Tea coming, from Kenya, the steady rise in oil prices in, the third quarter of 2017 contributing to a, higher GDP in key Tea importing nations, and the higher demand from Turkey and, Russia were all factors that augured well, for the price of Ceylon Tea in the world, market.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":300,"end":302,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":233,"end":238,"text":"Russia"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":221,"end":226,"text":"Turkey"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":171,"end":173,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":67,"end":71,"text":"Kenya"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":50,"end":52,"text":"Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":44,"end":52,"text":"black Tea"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":0,"end":2,"text":"Tea"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550090967000,"last_updated_at":1550090967000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Available industry data suggests the January–November cumulative average, for 2017 was Rs. 617.96 compared to Rs. 461.99 reported in 2016, showing a substantial gain of Rs.155.97. The high grown average totalling Rs. 598.60 recorded a gain of Rs. 155.89 vis-à-vis Rs. 442.71 of January- November 2016 while Medium Growns averaging, Rs.563.87 for January- November 2017 showed a gain of Rs. 149.74 vis-à-vis Rs. 414.13 of January- November 2016. Low Growns totalling Rs. 637.83 too show a substantial gain of Rs.157.7 vis-à-vis Rs. 480.13 of January-November 2016. Colombo Auction Averages Vs US$-2006 to 2017, SL.","annotation":[{"label":["LAW"],"points":[{"start":564,"end":587,"text":"Colombo Auction Averages"}]},{"label":["MONEY"],"points":[{"start":169,"end":177,"text":"Rs.155.97"}]},{"label":["DATE"],"points":[{"start":37,"end":52,"text":"January–November"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548143571000,"last_updated_at":1548143590000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "Rs (Source - Forbes and Walkers Research), US $, Exchange rate, SL.Rs to US$ KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, Sector Reviews Contd. Rubber SRI LANKA’S RUBBER INDUSTRY, Production Output, Unfavourable weather conditions had an adverse impact on Rubber production during, the ﬁrst half of 2017, where a decline of 5.9% was reported in comparison to the ﬁrst half of 2016. Sheet Rubber production, the largest component of total Rubber production, declined by 5.9% while crepe Rubber production decreased by 11.9% and the production of centrifuged latex and other categories of Rubber also recorded a decline of 2.9% during the ﬁrst half of 2017, compared to the corresponding period of the previous year. The decline in production was mainly attributable to intermittent wet weather throughout the, KELANI VALLEY PLANTATIONS PLC, Annual Report 2017/18, prices declined steadily and the year closed with latex crepe 1X being traded at Rs. 336/- per kg.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":922,"end":933,"text":"latex crepe "}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":596,"end":601,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":495,"end":500,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":447,"end":452,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":397,"end":402,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":265,"end":270,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":153,"end":158,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["FAC"],"points":[{"start":13,"end":39,"text":"Forbes and Walkers Research"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550211909000,"last_updated_at":1550211909000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "On other hand the RSS No.1 prices remained somewhat steady hovering between Rs. 325/- to Rs. 350/- per kg until end 2017, before declining steadily through the ﬁrst quarter of 2018 to reach Rs. 280/- per kg by end-March 2018. Traditionally the ﬁeld latex prices are based on the RSS 1 price.  As the RSS prices in Sri Lanka did not decline along with the world Rubber prices, the cost of centrifuged latex, produced in Sri Lanka remained high compared to that produced in other origin. This encouraged local Rubber good manufacturers to import the cheaper centrifuged latex, rather than use the local product.","annotation":[{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":556,"end":572,"text":"centrifuged latex"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":419,"end":427,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":388,"end":404,"text":"centrifuged latex"}]},{"label":["GPE"],"points":[{"start":314,"end":322,"text":"Sri Lanka"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1550065427000,"last_updated_at":1550065427000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
{"content": "As a result, most local centrifuged latex manufacturers were forced to either close or curtail operations in the last quarter of 2017/18. KVPL Rubber GSA, Nov Dec, ﬁrst half of the year and severe ﬂooding, in traditional Rubber growing areas in, May 2017, which caused heavy damage,, bringing a considerable number of estates, in the Southern and Western Provinces, to a complete standstill while yet others, became inaccessible due to the threat of, mudslides and landslides.","annotation":[{"label":["LOC"],"points":[{"start":334,"end":363,"text":"Southern and Western Provinces"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":221,"end":226,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":143,"end":148,"text":"Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":138,"end":148,"text":"KVPL Rubber"}]},{"label":["PRODUCT"],"points":[{"start":24,"end":40,"text":"centrifuged latex"}]}],"extras":null,"metadata":{"first_done_at":1548128444000,"last_updated_at":1548128444000,"sec_taken":0,"last_updated_by":"8FTDJONTxpa3dnMM35sEp5lK5EA2","status":"done","evaluation":"NONE"}}
